稍等一下
Just one sec.
这里是浴火餐厅 请稍等
Hasta El Fuego. Please hold.
好了
Okay.
这边请
This way.
就是这里 服务员马上就来
Here you are. Your server will be right with you.
-嘿 杰森 -嘿
Hey, Jason. Hey.
嗨 有想要喝的酒吗
Hi. Do you know what you want?
-有 -谢谢
- Uh, yeah. - Cool. Thanks.
嗨
Hi!
（雷吉 嗨）
（事情有点尴尬…）
（我迷路了）
（可以通话吗）
-再来一杯  -好的 好
Okay. - Another shot? - Yeah, sure. Okay.
（雷吉 来电…）
-嗨 雷吉 你好 -劳拉 嗨
Hi. Hi, Reggie. Laura, hi.
很高兴在这么尴尬的情况下跟你通话
Hello. Um, so nice to phone-meet you in this incredibly embarrassing way.
没事的 没关系
Oh, you know, no-- no problem. It's fine.
我选了一个不挂招牌的热门餐厅 活该找不到 对吧
This is what I get for picking a trendy place with no sign out front, huh?
对 这里的餐厅为什么这样
Yeah, why do they do that here? I don't know.
不知道 我来这座城市才几个月
I've only been in the city for a few months.
-我也是 真巧 对 -哇
Me, too! No way! Yeah. Oh, wow.
这家餐厅很酷
Well, um, it's a very cool restaurant.
-它是在哈德逊街道上吗  -对
Is it on Hudson? Yes.
-我在哈德逊街道上吗  -我不知道
Am I on Hudson? I don't know.
我不是在哈德逊街道上 见鬼
I am not on Hudson. Shit.
我现在朝哈德逊街道走去
Uh, I am now walking towards Hudson.
-好的 -真的非常抱歉
Okay. I am so, so sorry.
我也不想给一个大学教授 留这样的第一印象
This is not the first impression I wanted to make on a college professor.
是副教授而已 而且只是电影研究专业的…
Oh, pfft. Associate Professor, and it's just Film Studies,
所以别担心
so... you're safe.
电影研究 好酷啊
Film Studies? That's... ...cool.
说起来很酷 但你给一群19岁的宿醉学生
You say that, but try teaching a class on 20th-century slashers
讲授20世纪的砍杀电影试试
to a heap of hungover 19-year-olds.
砍杀电影 你最喜欢哪部恐怖电影
Slashers, huh? What's your favorite scary movie?
反正不是《血腥刺杀》
Um, not that one.
你为什么研究砍杀电影
So why slashers?
我觉得这类电影很有意思
Well, I just, you know, I think it's interesting.
你可以通过研究当时的桥段
You can really examine the culture of the moment
来了解那时候的文化
by looking at the tropes of the time.
比如蒙面的杀手 最后幸存的少女 还有各种禁忌
Like, um, the masked killer, the final girl, the different rules:
不要掉队 不要做爱
Don't split up. Don't have sex.
-还有不要接电话 -对 没错
Don't answer the phone. Exactly, exactly, exactly.
全是各种套路
It's all cliché.
但这些套路为小众艺术开辟了一条道路
But out of those clichés comes an opportunity for outsider art.
可以说是失声者的发声渠道
A voice for the voiceless, you might say.
又在说教了
Jesus Christ.
好吧 老实说 我更喜欢浪漫喜剧片
Yeah, I'm more of a rom-com guy, to be honest.
-好 我好像到哈德逊街道了 -好的
Okay, I think I'm on Hudson. Okay.
餐厅的外饰是什么颜色的
What color is the outside of the restaurant?
好像是红色
I-I think it's red.
我没看到红色外饰的餐厅
I don't see anything red.
可能是我记错了 我…
I, um-- I could be wrong. Let me just, um...
我去看看
Let me go have a little look-see.
好的 谢谢
Oh, okay. Thank you.
对 确实是红色
Yep, it's definitely red.
好吧 我在这里没看到红色外饰的餐厅
Yeah, I'm not seeing anything red here.
你确定在哈德逊街道上
Sure you're on Hudson?
该死的 还要走一个街区
Um... Oh, crap, I'm still a block over.
那边似乎有条小巷 我可以抄近路
It looks like there's an alley I can cut through.
餐厅是不是在一条小巷附近
Is the restaurant near an alley?
对 这里是有一条小巷
Yes! Yes. There is an alley.
太好了 我这就穿过小巷
Oh, perfect. I'm coming down the alley.
我没看到你
I don't see you.
等等 真的吗 你确定吗
Wait. Really? Are you sure?
小巷的中间有几个垃圾桶
Uh, there are some dumpsters about halfway down.
我看到了 但没看到你
I see them, but I don't see you.
对 我也没看到你
Yeah, I don't see you, either.
这有点诡异 对吧
This is creepy, right?
有一点
Uh, a little bit.
你研究20世纪的砍杀电影
20th-century slashers, huh?
对 你确定正在朝哈德逊街道走吗
Yeah. Are you sure you're walking towards Hudson?
我确定
I'm sure.
等等 我好像看到你了 你能挥手吗
Oh, wait, I think I see you! Can you wave?
你看到我了吗
Can you see me?
我看的那个人没挥手 对方正盯着我
Uh, the person I'm looking at isn't waving. They're just staring at me.
真的吗
Are you sure?
好吧 情况不对劲
Okay, this is weird.
现在对方正朝我走来
Now they're moving towards me.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
该死 他在跟着我
Shit. He's following me.
我一个人都没看到
I don't see anybody.
该死 他在追我
Holy shit! He's after me!
你在哪里
Where are you?
-他拿着一把刀 -什么
He's got a knife! What?
这还不是最可怕的
And that's not the worst part.
最可怕的是…
The worst part is...
你明明在教砍杀电影的课
...you teach a class about slashers
却仍然敢一个人走进黑暗的巷子里
and you still walked into a dark alley.
好了 这不好玩
Alone. Okay, that's not funny.
不
No.
是不好玩
It's not.
现在我看到红色了
Now I see something red.
（布莱克摩尔大学）
嘿 塔拉
Oh, hey. Tara!
杰森
Jason.
你和格雷格要参加OKB派对吗
Are you and Greg gonna come to the OKB party?
如果他能及时完成西语作业的话 我们会参加
Well, if he finishes his Spanish project in time, yes, we will.
你姐姐参加吗
Is your sister coming?
不 萨曼莎绝对不会参加兄弟会的派对
No, Sam wouldn't be caught dead at a frat party.
凡事都有第一次嘛
There's a first time for everything.
但今晚不可能
Not tonight, though.
-你就不能劝劝她吗  -那不是我的事 是你的事
- Can't convince her? - No. That's not my problem, that's yours.
-给我留一杯 -好的 派对上见
- Save me a drink! - All right. I'll see you.
亲爱的 我回来了
Honey, I'm home!
格雷格
Greg?
（格雷格来电）
对不起 好吗
I'm sorry, okay?
我期盼太久了 而且我需要练手
I-- I just got massive blue balls, and I-- I had to practice.
千万别生气 你有多生气
Please don't be mad. How mad are you?
我没生气 杰森
Oh, I'm not mad, Jason.
兄弟 我们说好 不在我们两人之间用这个声音的
Dude. We said we wouldn't use the voice on each other.
我们说好的事多了去了
We said a lot of things.
你是格雷格吧
This is Greg, right?
要不然还能是谁
Who else would it be?
你在哪里 我想跟你聊杀劳拉的感受
Where are you? I want to tell you about it.
噢 对了
Oh, by the way,
我们应该参加那个兄弟会的派对 塔拉也去
we should go to that frat party. Tara's going.
-那是什么感觉  -别在电话上说 兄弟
What was it like? Not on the phone, man.
还有 说真的 赶快关掉那该死的变声器
Seriously, turn off the fucking voice modulator.
我只是想练习用这个声音说话
I'm just trying to get the voice right.
你要练手 我也要练声
You got to have your practice, I get mine.
随便吧
Whatever.
快跟我说那是什么感觉
Just tell me what it felt like.
你说了我也许就会现身
Then maybe I'll come out.
兄弟 我知道你不在公寓里
Dude, I know you're not here.
你就顺我的意吧
Humor me.
好 行吧
All right, fine.
那种感觉比我们想象的还要好
It was even better than we ever could have imagined.
当刀刺进她身体里的时候
I mean, when the knife went in her,
感觉她不再是人类了
it's like she wasn't human anymore.
就只是一个动物
Just an animal.
刀扎得越多
And every time it went in,
她就越不像人类
she was less and less human.
然后…
And then,
她就只是一团死肉
she was just meat.
但她不是一团死肉 杰森
But she wasn't just meat, Jason.
她是一个人 我们电影课的教授
She was a person. Our film professor.
对 好吧…
Yeah, well,
去她的
fuck her.
她给我的意式恐怖电影论文评了个C减
She gave me a C-minus on my giallo paper.
你杀她就为了这个 就因为一个C减
Is that why you killed her? Because of the C-minus?
你接下来要杀谁 你的小学副校长
Who's next, your grade-school vice principal?
你知道下一个要杀谁 你怎么这么怪
You know who's next. Why are you being like this?
行啦 杰森 我们都认识多久了
Come on, Jason. How long have we known each other?
你说呢
You tell me.
八年 我们是在初中认识的 在亚特兰大
Eight years. We met in junior high. In Atlanta.
我只是想让你亲口告诉我 你为什么要当鬼面杀手
I just want you to tell me why you think you're doing this. In your words.
我们要完成里奇的电影
We're finishing Richie's film.
没错 要杀的是萨曼莎和塔拉
That's right, by killing Sam and Tara.
你为什么奚落我
Why are you fucking with me?
你为什么不愿意说你在哪里
Why won't you tell me where you are?
你为什么一直问这个问题  我已经告诉你了
Why do you keep asking me that? I already told you.
我在公寓里
I'm here.
我们玩一个游戏
Let's play a game.
烦人
Shit.
你知道“近热远冷”这个游戏吗
Do you know Warmer, Colder?
快 找到我 然后我们去捅死卡彭特姐妹
Come on, find me. And then we'll go and cut up the Carpenter sisters.
你在用该死的摄像头监视我
Are you using the fucking cameras?
对 摄像头
Yeah. The cameras.
现在你很冷
And at the moment, you're very, very cold.
好吧 浑球 玩就玩
All right, douchebag, let's play.
冷
Cold.
升温了
Heating up.
变热了
Warmer.
够了 这太蠢了 我要挂电话了
All right, you know what? This is stupid. I'm gonna hang up now.
但你已经升温了
But you're getting warmer.
变冷了
Colder.
变热了
Warmer.
更热了
很会找嘛
You're on fire!
操
Oh, fuck!
你觉得自己像动物吗 杰森
Do you feel like an animal, Jason?
求你停手
Please, stop!
像死肉吗
Like meat?
但我们还要完成电影
But we have to finish the movie.
谁在乎什么电影
Who gives a fuck about movies?
《惊声尖叫6》
新药的效果怎么样
So how are the new meds treating you?
我觉得还可以
Okay, I think.
没再出现不该有的幻视
Still not seeing anyone I shouldn't be.
但我真正担心的是塔拉
What I'm really worried about, though, is Tara.
我真正担心的是你
What I'm really worried about is you.
你来接受治疗已经有六个月了
You've been coming here for six months now,
但你和我谈的全都是你妹妹没有认真对待
and all we've really spoken about is how your sister isn't dealing with
你们在一年前所经受的遭遇
whatever happened to both of you a year ago.
你提到了一段虐待关系
Now, you've alluded to an abusive relationship,
还提到了跟生父相关的心理问题
issues with your father,
但每当我鼓励你跟我谈细节时
but every time I push you for specifics,
你总是避而不谈
you shut down.
我不敢信任别人
I have trust issues.
好吧
Okay.
如果你需要我帮你
If I'm going to help you,
你就得跟我说细节
um, I-- I need you to give me the details.
好吧
Okay.
我的父亲是比利鲁米斯
My father was Billy Loomis.
他是恶名昭彰的连环杀人犯
He was a famous serial killer.
有人还以他为原型拍了一部电影
They made a movie about him.
对 没错
Yeah. Mm-hmm. Certainly did.
去年我发现我的男友也是个连环杀人犯
Last year I found out that my boyfriend was also a serial killer
他之所以跟我交往 是因为他崇拜我的生父
and only dating me because he idolized my father.
他和他的癫狂女友杀了很多人
Him and his psycho girlfriend killed a bunch of people.
当我是比利的女儿这件事被公开后
And when it got out that I'm Billy's daughter,
网上开始传播一个荒谬的谣言
this crazy rumor started online
说是我策划了整个系列杀人案 并栽赃给他们
that I orchestrated the whole thing and framed them.
（萨曼莎卡彭特 才是伍德小镇的杀人真凶）
（里奇是被栽赃的无辜人士）
里奇是我的男友
Richie was my boyfriend.
（萨曼莎卡彭特去死吧）
但你没杀人
But you didn't.
-当然没有 -好的
- Of course not. - Okay.
他差点杀了我妹妹和我
He almost killed my sister and me,
后来我阻止了他
before I stopped him.
好的 你是怎么…
Okay, and how...
你是怎么阻止他的
How-how did you stop him?
我给他扎了22刀 割了他的喉
Well, I stabbed him 22 times and slit his throat.
然后我开枪打他的头
And then I shot him in the head.
但我来做心理治疗不是因为这事
But that's not why I'm here.
是因为什么
Why are you here?
因为…
Because...
我尝到了一种快感
it felt right.
我…
I...
治疗到此为止吧
I think we're done here.
什么 不 是你让我跟你说细节的 我只是…
What? No, you said give you details. I'm just--
我能力不足 解决不了这样的心理问题
I-- I'm not equipped to deal with this kind of thing.
拜托了 斯通医生 我需要你的帮助
Please, Dr. Stone. I'm asking for your help.
按法律规定 我需要将你的情况 向有关当局上报
By law, I'm required to report this to the authorities.
上报 上报什么
Report it? Report what?
我没说我要杀人呀
I didn't say I was gonna do anything.
你确实没有直说
Not explicitly, no.
你知道吗
You know what?
算了吧
Forget it.
你和那些轻信谣言的人没两样
You're just like all the others.
嘿 我是塔拉 给我发信息吧
Hey, you've reached Tara. Why aren't you texting me?
你应该接我的电话
You know you're supposed to pick up when I call.
我提前结束治疗了
I got out of therapy early,
我在想也许我们可以一起做晚餐
so I was thinking maybe we cook dinner tonight.
如果你想的话 再见
If you want. I'll see you soon.
嘿
Hey!
塔拉
Tara?
奎茵
Quinn?
我们太大声了吗
Were we being too loud?
完全没有 你看到塔拉了吗
Not at all. Have you seen Tara?
你别生气
Don't be mad.
-我为什么要生气  -因为你会生气
- Why would I be mad? - Because you get mad.
那是保罗吗
Is that Paul?
保罗是哪个浑蛋
Who the fuck is Paul?
我发现生活
Life, I have found,
就应该多多丰富口味
is about variety.
好吧
Okay.
-这封信是你的 -谢谢
- Uh, this one's yours. - Thanks.
-塔拉呢  -她去参加OKB兄弟会的派对了
Where's Tara? She went to the Omega Kappa Beta party.
我已经劝她别去了
I begged her not to go to that!
你果然生气了
And we've now arrived at mad.
你知不知道她有没有带泰瑟枪
Do you know if she at least took her Taser?
我不知道她参加这个兄弟会的派对 武装得多全面
I cannot speak to how heavily armed Tara is at this fraternity party.
宝贝 你要回来“再战”吗
Babe, you coming back?
-“宝贝”  -不知道他为什么这样叫
"Babe"? I don't know.
又是那个赤膊帅哥
Ooh, is Cute Boy shirtless again?
-谁是赤膊帅哥 宝贝  -始终都是你
- Who's Cute Boy, babe? - Always you...
亲爱的
sweetie.
你们已经眉来眼去几个月了
You guys have been checking each other out for months.
为什么不直接去找他聊聊
Why don't you just talk to him?
因为隔窗对望 已经是我传情互动的极限了
Because that right there is about all the romantic interaction I'm ready for.
-我要去找塔拉 -好吧
- I'm gonna go find Tara. - Okay.
-马上回来 -拜拜
- Be right back. - Bye.
该死
Damn.
-你好吗 兄弟  -再来一罐啤酒吗
What up, man? Where can I get another beer?
天啊 劳拉 你好吗
Hey, guys. Oh, my God, Lou, how are you?
你不觉得后怕吗
It doesn't bother you?
你们就是在一个居家派对上
Being at a house party after you were almost
差点被捅死的 还敢参加居家派对
brutally murdered at a house party?
不怕 我觉得这种事就跟被雷劈一样
No, I think of it like being struck by lightning.
一个人被雷劈两次的概率是极低的
The odds of it happening twice to the same person are extremely low.
那我就跟定你了
Guess I should stay close to you then.
-糟糕 抱歉 -当心
Shit, I'm sorry. Watch out.
嗨
Hi.
你怎么样 塔塔
How are you doing, T?
很好
Hi.
你在装样子
You're lying.
我没装 上一桶确实空了
No, last one's kicked.
但厨房里有一些烈酒
We got some hard stuff in the kitchen, though.
我叫弗兰奇
Frankie.
塔拉
Tara.
你带路吧
Lead the way.
你是OBZ姐妹会的人
You Omega Beta Zeta?
不 还不是 但我可能会参加招募
No, not yet. But I might rush it.
噢 你是大一新生 好的
Oh, freshman. Right on!
你是哪里人
Where from?
密歇根
Michigan.
好的
All right.
你知道吗
You know what?
我楼上的房间里有一瓶火龙威士忌
I got a bottle of Fireball up in my room.
不管了 好啊 走
Fuck it. Yeah, go.
噢 我可不喜欢这状况
Uh... Oh, I don't love that.
嘿 你想回去吗
Hey! You want to call it a night?
不想…
No, uh...
我还想留下来玩一会儿
I think that I'm actually still gonna hang,
你们想走的话不用等我
but you guys don't have to wait for me.
别担心 我会照顾她的 我叫弗兰奇
Don't worry. I'll take care of her. I'm Frankie.
我一点都不想了解你这个人
And I'm spectacularly uninterested in knowing anything about you.
不 姐妹 安妮卡 我没有喝迷糊
No, dude, Anika, I'm not that bad.
但谢谢你关心我
But I appreciate you looking out for me.
让我看看你的气势
Let me see it in your face.
近一点
Closer. Closer.
好
All right, all right.
为我们这个活力二人组干杯
Cheers, man, to the dynamic duo
霍顿斯公寓3层315宿舍的死党
of Hortense Tower, third floor, room 315.
好了 是时候发动攻势了
Oh, man. Time to start making moves.
快去舞池 去认识一些妹子
Yeah, get you out there. Introduce you to some girls!
她怎么样
What about her?
她很漂亮
She's gorgeous.
-好啊 约她出去 -不 不行
- Great. Ask her out. - No, I can't.
快去约她
Ask her out. Ask her out.
别说了
Shut up!
你得自信点 而且看看你 兄弟 你多诱人啊
Got to have confidence. Plus, look at you, man! You're a snack!
你自己就是一个诱人的帅哥
Practically an entire meal all on your own.
-真的吗  -对 你可是伊森兰德里
- Really? - Yeah. You're Ethan Landry.
嘿 打扰一下
Hey, excuse me!
-查德 -嗨 你好吗
- Chad. - Howdy. How you doing?
这是我的朋友 很诱人 对吧
My friend here, he's a snack, right?
-那是什么意思  -是好的意思
- What did that mean? - No, it's good.
-什么  -反正不差
- What? - It's not bad.
有提升的空间
There's room for improvement!
嘿 猛男 我们需要你
Hey, big guy, you're needed.
拜拜
See ya.
你不是去年在加利福尼亚 被人模仿《血腥刺杀》加害的女生吗
Aren't you that girl involved in that "Stab" shit in California last year?
不 是另一个海盗装女生
No. That's a different pirate.
嘿 伙计
Hey, partner!
塔拉在下面玩就好
Tara's good down here.
抱歉 兄弟 我没听清
Sorry, bro, I didn't catch that.
你听清了
Yeah, you did.
不 查德
No, Chad.
-没事 是我要上去 -对 看到了吗 查德
- It's fine. I want to. - Yeah, see, Chad?
-没事的 -她要上去
- It's okay. - She wants to.
-你的脏手别碰她 -别碰我
- Get your fucking hands off her. - Get the fuck off me!
男生们
Guys!
你这算什么 拐骗女生
Who the fuck are you, Risky Business?
-别吵了 -男士们
Stop! Guys, guys!
抱歉打断一下 我马上就要电击你的蛋蛋了
Sorry to interrupt. I'm just gonna tase you in the balls real quick.
别再碰我妹妹
Don't ever lay hands on my sister.
你这个贱人
You fucking bitch!
-操 -萨曼莎
Sam. Fuck you!
你在开什么玩笑
Are you fucking kidding me?
你在跟踪我
You're stalking me now?
天啊 是那个变态女生
Holy shit, it's that psycho girl!
就是她吗
That's her?
塔拉 你能不能停一下
Tara. Will you stop?
我简直不敢相信你会那样做 你这是丢我的脸
I cannot believe you did that! You embarrassed me.
那个人就是个浑球 他想占你的便宜
That guy was a dick. He was gonna take advantage of you.
-所以呢  -所以
- So? - So?
就算我要跟一个浑球上床 那也是我自己的决定
If I want to hook up with an asshole, that's my decision!
-是我的决定 跟你没关系 -好吧
- It's my decision. - Okay.
你在我的生活中消失了五年
It's not about you! You're out of my life for five years,
现在你连五分钟的自由都不给我
and then you can't leave me alone for five minutes.
因为你不认真对待过去的遭遇
Because you're not dealing with what happened to us.
你去见过那个心理咨询师一次吗
Have you even gone to see the counselor once?
-没有 我不打算去 -为什么
No, I'm not going to. Why not?
因为我不像你 我根本就不想活在过去
Because I'm uninterested in living in the past like you are.
-你这是什么意思  -姑娘们 别吵了
- What's that supposed to mean? - Guys, come on.
意思是我不会让那三天的遭遇
It means I'm not gonna let what happened to us for three days
影响我的余生
define the rest of my life.
所以你要假装事情没发生过
So you're just gonna pretend it never happened.
你来纽约是做什么的 萨曼莎
What are you doing here, Sam? In New York.
好吧 你做着两份寒酸的工作 来支付房租
You're working two shitty jobs to help with rent, whatever,
但你有什么规划
but what's your plan?
我有自己的规划
I know what I'm gonna do.
好吗 我要继续上大学
Okay? Because I'm gonna keep going to college,
我要获得学位 过自己的生活
I'm gonna get my degree, and I'm gonna live my life.
我的生活
My life.
好吗 我有规划
Okay? I know.
但你跟我来到这里 不肯让我离开你的视线
You just followed me here, and you won't let me out of your sight.
-我只是想保护你 -我…
I'm just trying to look out for you. I--
我知道
I know.
我知道你想保护我
I know you are.
但你保护不了我一辈子
You can't do it for the rest of my life, though.
你得对我放手
You have to let me go.
嘿
Hey!
杀人凶手
Murderer!
你有什么毛病 贱人
What the fuck is wrong with you, bitch?
你对我有意见
You got a problem with me?
你们离她远点 她做过什么自己清楚
You guys should stay away from her. She knows what she did.
我什么都没做
I didn't fucking do anything!
是啊 贱人
Sure, bitch.
走开
Walk away!
-我受够这种事了 -冷静
I'm so sick of this shit. Hey, calm down. Come on.
如果你要纸巾的话 我有
Hey, I have tissues if you want tissues.
我有三张纸巾
I have, like, three tissues.
嘿
Hey.
抱歉我跟萨曼莎说了你的去向
I'm sorry I told Sam where you went.
没关系 我只是…
It's fine. I just...
她对我过度保护了
She's all the way up my ass.
就像往常一样
Like usual.
我懂被家人过度掌控是什么感受
I know what it's like when they hold on too tight.
在我们…
After we, um...
失去我的哥哥后…
lost my brother,
我的爸爸就不愿意让我独处
my dad wouldn't leave me alone.
我上大学后 他甚至转到了纽约警察局 所以…
He even transferred to the NYPD when I got into college, so...
像个跟踪狂
Stalker much?
我出去了 让你们…聊聊
I'm gonna go, let you guys... chat.
谢谢
Thank you.
你可以…
You can, um,
回你的宿舍了
go back to your dorm.
我们今天肯定不会再吵了
I'm pretty sure the fighting is done for the day.
那真可惜
That's too bad.
我还想着趁机练一下拳呢
I was actually looking forward to getting some shots in while I can.
-是吗  -对
- Oh, yeah? - Yeah.
放马过来
Bring it.
谢谢
Thank you
谢谢拦着不让我上楼
for not letting me go up those stairs.
不知道怎么回事 也许我刚才没意识到 自己已经喝迷糊了
Yeah, I don't know, I think I was just more messed up than I realized.
幸存者就应该抱团在一起
Survivors got to stick together... you know.
而且你可以找到更好的男伴 而不是趁约会下手的弗兰奇
And besides, you can do a lot better than Date Rape Frankie.
塔拉 你…
Tara, you're...
我觉得你非常特别
I think you're really special.
我现在已经清醒了
I'm not messed up anymore.
我就是知会一下
Just so you know.
好的
Okay.
我忘记拿手机了
I forgot my phone.
我刚刚横插一鸟了
Did I cock-block you?
-你说什么  -横插一鸟 -不
- What did you just say? - I cock-blocked you. - No.
-我打断了你们的好事 对吗  -当然没有
I cock-blocked you, didn't I? Immediate no.
别再说“鸟”这个词了
Please stop saying the word "cock."
-你有什么事 -拿手机
What did you need? My phone.
-别再像刚才那样乱闯别人的房间了 -不会了
Don't ever enter a room - like that again. - I won't.
-那样很鲁莽 -我走了
- No, it was rude. - I'm gonna go.
你好好休息 醒醒酒
But get some rest, get sober,
然后不要再为难你姐姐了 好吗  她很爱你
and please don't kill your sister, okay? She loves you very much.
-晚安 -拜拜
Good night! Bye-bye.
-奎茵… -抱歉
Quinn... I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
真见鬼
Fuck.
当心
Careful.
会被别人发现的
Someone might see us.
你说的话总是这么“浪漫”
You always say the most romantic things.
-丹尼 -怎么了
- Danny. - What?
我迷恋“只敢偷偷摸摸跟我在一起的女人” 这样说你安心了吗
Can I help it if my kink is "woman who's ashamed to be seen with me"?
好啦 你知道不是那样的 我只是…
Come on. You know it's not that. I'm just
-还没准备好… -我知道 没准备好让你妹妹和朋友们知道
not ready for-- I know, for your sister and your friends to know
你喜欢跟人进行身体接触
that you enjoy physical contact with another human being.
我理解你 真的 我不会说出去的
I get it, I do. Your secret is safe with me.
我想说一件小事…不是什么大不了的事
A little thing-- It's not a big deal--
我闻到你身上明显有樱桃可乐味
I just can't help but notice that you're covered in Cherry Coke.
我很确定这是无糖樱桃可乐味
Um, I'm pretty sure it's Diet Cherry Coke, actually.
-怎么 你不喜欢  -不 我很喜欢 真的
- What, you don't like it? -No, I love it! I do.
这是个香甜撩人的好选择
It's a very sensual, aromatic choice.
你又遇到了发疯的阴谋论者
Was that another conspiracy nut?
出名并不像大家想的那样风光
Being famous isn't all it's cracked up to be.
而且塔拉又生我的气了
And Tara's pissed at me. Again.
她说要我对她放手
She says she wants me to let her go.
对 家人有时候会很伤人
Yeah, family can be rough.
萨曼莎
Sam!
赶快上来
Get up here right now!
我正站在这栋公寓大楼的前面
I'm standing in front of the apartment building...
-怎么了  -两名学生的残体…
What's going on? ...where the mutilated bodies
-就是在这里… -帅哥 好样的
of two students... Cute Boy. Nice.
…被发现的 警方刚才公布了两人的名字
...were discovered. Their names have just been released by police.
（受害者是布莱克摩尔大学的学生）
杰森卡维和格雷格布鲁克纳
Jason Carvey and Greg Bruckner.
天啊 那是我们电影研究课上的恐女自闭男
Holy shit, that's that chode from our Film Studies class!
痴迷达里奥恐怖电影的学生
The one obsessed with Argento. Also found at the scene
另外案发现场还发现了多件鬼面服装
were various Ghostface costumes,
这是个因为《血腥刺杀》电影系列 而出名的角色
a character popularized by theStab movie franchise.
收拾行李 我们十分钟后离开
Pack a bag. We leave in ten.
萨曼莎 等等 萨曼莎
Sam! Wait, Sam!
-我们要离开这座城市 -什么
- We're getting out of the city. - What?
谢谢 可疑的新来者 但接下来交给我们吧
Thank you, suspicious new guy, but we got it from here.
晚安 平安回家 走吧
Have a good night. Get home safe. Go, go, go.
萨曼莎
Sam!
Sam, wh--
-等等 -跟我来
-Hold on. - Come on.
不 等等 我们谈一谈
No, wait, let's talk about this for a second.
这也许跟我们没有半点关系
'Cause this might not have anything to do with us.
-你开什么玩笑  -这是座大城市
- Are you serious? - It's a big city!
万圣节要到了 戴面具正常
It's Halloween. Everybody's wearing masks!
-这说不准 -塔拉 这不是巧合
- You don't know. - Tara, this isn't a coincidence.
你认识那个人
You knew him!
-不太熟 -查德 明迪 帮我说话
- Barely. -Chad, Mindy, back me up.
这确实有点…
It is a little bit...
似曾相识
Close to home.
看吧
See?
奎茵 你爸爸是警察 对吧
Quinn, your dad's a cop, right?
可以打电话问问他是怎么回事吗
Can you call him and find out what's going on?
免得你单方面决定要我放弃大学的学业
Before you make the unilateral decision
然后逃离这个州
to abandon my college education and flee the fucking state!
我现在打给他
I'm calling him now.
谢谢
Thank you.
是谁
Who is it?
（盖尔威瑟斯 拒接）
为什么她的电话一响 你们都如临大敌
Why did everyone just freak out when her phone rang?
你补一下功课 兄弟
You got to keep up, my dude.
萨曼莎
Sam?
我爸爸要跟你通话
My dad wants to talk to you.
-贝利先生 嗨 -嘿 萨曼莎
Mr. Bailey, hi. Hey, Sam.
（萨曼莎卡彭特）
我刚才正要打电话给你
I was actually just about to call you.
我妹妹觉得我可能反应过度了
Well, my sister thinks I'm probably overreacting.
不 很遗憾 你没有反应过度
No, unfortunately, you're not.
这是什么意思 发生了什么事
What do you mean? What's going on?
恐怕你得来局里一趟
I'm afraid I need you to come down to the station.
萨曼莎 慢点
Sam, slow down.
塔拉 不 快回去 锁好门
Tara, no. Get back inside, lock the door.
开什么玩笑  你现在又不想形影不离了
Are you serious? Now you don't want to stick together?
好吧
Fine.
（来电 里奇基尔希）
怎么可能
What the fuck?
我没删他的联系方式
I never deleted his contact.
-这是用他的号码打来的 -别接
This is coming - from his number. - Don't pick that up.
就让它响吧
Just let it ring.
萨曼莎
Sam.
-是谁  -你好啊 萨曼莎
Who is this? Hello, Samantha.
你想我吗
Did you miss me?
我劝你先好好考虑再决定要不要骚扰我
I want you to think long and hard about whether you really want to do this.
因为之前骚扰我们的两个人都没命了
Because the last two people that fucked with us ended up dead.
你应该感谢我 萨曼莎
You should be thanking me, Sam.
杰森和格雷格原本计划要杀你和你妹妹呢
Jason and Greg were gonna kill you and your sister.
我在他们下手前剖了他们的腹
I gutted them before they had the chance.
所以呢 你现在要保护我们
So what? You're protecting us now?
也不是
Not quite.
我要让全世界都看到你的真面目
I'm going to show the world who you really are:
你是个骗子和杀人犯
A liar and a killer.
我要惩罚你 萨曼莎
I'm going to punish you, Sam.
你真不应该轻信网上的传言 浑蛋
You shouldn't believe everything you read on the Internet, asshole.
别嚣张 我会让你血债血偿的
Don't be cute. You're gonna pay for what you did.
在捅死你之前 我是不会停手的
And I'm not gonna stop until I butcher you.
你和挡道的人都得死
You and anyone who gets between us.
你和塔拉最好当心身后
You and Tara better watch your backs.
你才要当心身后
You better watch yours.
不
No! No!
快 快跑
Run!
快点
Come on!
救命 拜托
Help! Please!
到里面去
In there!
帮帮我们
Please help us!
-我们刚才被袭击了 -快报警
- We were just attacked. - Call 911!
大家都在排队呢 女士们
There's a fucking line here, girls.
你有什么事吗 兄弟
You got a problem here, guy?
-从后门出去 -谢谢
- Go out the back! - Thank you!
-该死 锁住了 -钥匙 我们需要钥匙
-Fuck, it's locked. - Keys! We need your keys!
-当心 -小心
- Look out! - Watch out!
等等
Wait.
等等 不要
Wait, wait! No, no, no!
跑 快 快跑
Run! Go! Run!
-到后面看看 -后退 女士
Let's go. Going round back.
我们在公寓案发现场的尸体旁 发现了这个
This was found next to the body at the apartment crime scene.
DNA检测显示这是里奇基尔希的面具
DNA says that it belonged to someone named Richie Kirsch.
你们认得他吗
Does that ring a bell?
我们很熟悉他
We're familiar with him.
但袭击我们的那个人戴的是另一个面具
But the one that attacked us had a different mask on.
那个面具更破旧 感觉使用的年头更长
It was kind of more beat up. Like it was older.
我得问你们…
I got to ask...
你们今晚早些时候有不在场证据吗
do you have alibis for earlier tonight?
我和朋友参加了一个派对
I was at a party with my friends.
我去见了心理治疗师
I was at my therapist's.
我可以把他的联系信息给你 有需要的话你可以联系他核实
I can give you his information. You can call to check if you want.
然后我去那个派对找塔拉
And then I met Tara at that party,
在那里电击了一个人
where I tased someone.
跟案子无关
Unrelated.
那是在这之前还是之后
Was that before or after this happened?
-杀人凶手 -你有什么毛病 贱人
Murderer! What the fuck is wrong with you, bitch?
你对我有意见
You got a problem with me?
之前
Before.
重点是 我们整晚都跟别人在一起
The point is, we were with people all night.
我们室友的爸爸
So, our roommate's dad
竟然恰巧负责我们的案子
just happened to pull our case.
-这真是个不可思议的巧合 对吧  -对
- That'd be a crazy coincidence, right? - Yeah.
负责这个案子的警探把案件交给了我
The detective who had the case, he offered it to me
因为这牵扯到奎茵
because it involves Quinn.
但如果你们反感的话 我完全可以交回去
Um, but I can totally give it back if you're uncomfortable.
看你们的意思
It's up to you.
没关系
It's fine.
所以如果袭击你的人确实偷了你的证件
So if the man who attacked you did steal your license
并故意放在尸体旁边…
and plant it next to the body,
那么对方可能是你们亲近的人
it'd probably be somebody close to you.
你们跟朋友认识多久了
How long have you known your friends?
大概六个月之前 我们和明迪 查德一起搬来上暑期课
Well, we moved here with Mindy and Chad for summer semester, like, six months ago.
奎茵 伊森和安妮卡都是那时候认识的
So, Quinn, um, Ethan, Anika-- all since then.
我可以为奎茵的为人打包票 所以可以排除一个嫌疑人了
I think I can vouch for Quinn, so that's one less we have to worry about.
你们俩有认识 可能会以你们为攻击目标的人吗
Do either of you have anyone that might want to target you?
认识的已经死了
Not anyone who's still alive.
哇
Yikes.
FBI的人来了 要争夺管辖权
FBI's here, claiming jurisdiction.
他们在哪里
Where are they?
有什么可以帮忙的吗
Can I help you?
我是FBI探员可碧里德 来自亚特兰大办事处
Special Agent Kirby Reed, FBI. I work out of the Atlanta office.
噢 你是迷路了吗
Oh. You lost?
你的两个受害人来纽约上大学前 是我们市的居民
Your two vics were residents of my city before they moved here for college.
我前几个月一直在调查
I have been investigating their online activity
他们的网络活动
for the past few months.
哇
Wow.
为什么
Why?
我对鬼面袭击案特别感兴趣
I take a special interest in Ghostface attacks.
-可碧  -嘿 萨曼莎
- Kirby? - Hey, Sam.
你怎么来了
What?
塔拉
Tara.
你就是那个FBI探员
You're the FBI?
-你们认识  -对
- You guys know each other? - Yeah.
我们是伍德小镇高中的校友 我读高一时她在毕业班
We went to Woodsboro High together. She was a senior when I was a freshman.
对 我们有相同的经历
We share a certain history, yeah.
我不是来抢管辖权的
I'm not trying to get into a jurisdictional pissing contest here,
我只是想提供协助
I just want to help.
给你看我收集的信息 希望你也礼尚往来
I'll show you mine, et cetera.
谢谢
Thank you.
袭击者把面具留在了那家杂货店
He left this mask at the bodega.
我们检测到两个人的DNA
DNA traces of two individuals,
查理沃克和吉尔罗伯茨 两人都已不在人世
Charlie Walker, Jill Roberts, both deceased.
是2011年的鬼面杀手
The Ghostface killers of 2011.
这就是查理沃克的手笔
Charlie Walker gave me this.
我说过 我对这些案件特别感兴趣
Like I said, I take a special interest.
那个人袭击你们时 是戴着这个面具吗
Is this the mask he was wearing when he attacked you?
不是
No.
所以对方是故意把面具留在现场的
So he's leaving them on purpose.
这表明做这件事的人 是以前那些凶手的追随者
Which means whoever's doing this is a student of the killers who came before.
也许那个人认为萨曼莎是最新的鬼面杀手
Maybe he believes Sam is the latest in a long line.
好吧 祝你们查得顺利
Yeah, good luck with that.
我们要出城
We're getting out of town.
很遗憾 不行
I'm sorry, that's not possible.
你们俩是两起杀人案的嫌疑人
You're both persons of interest in a double homicide,
所以你们不准出城 很抱歉
so you're not allowed to leave town. Sorry.
-你开玩笑吗  -他说得对
- Are you serious? - He's right.
-但如果我们携手合作… -我们走
But if we work together--We're going.
她们出来了
They're coming out
萨曼莎 对于昨晚的凶杀案 你有不在场证明吗
Samantha, do you have an alibi for last night's murders?
塔拉 你在你姐姐身边有安全感吗
Tara, do you feel safe around your sister?
塔拉
Tara! Tara!
我是四频道的盖尔威瑟斯
Gale Weathers, Channel 4.
你们觉得是你们
Do you ladies think you're the reason
把鬼面杀手引来纽约的吗
the Ghostface killer has come to the Big Apple?
身手不错 亲爱的 但这种场面我见多了
Nice try, sweetie, but I've done this dance before.
-离我们远点 -萨曼莎
Stay away from us.
你们还生我的气
Are you still mad at me?
你说过不会把发生的事写成书
You said you wouldn't write a book about what happened.
结果你却言而无信
And then you wrote a book about what happened.
拜托
Oh, come on.
总会有人写的 这是我的工作
Somebody was gonna write about it! It's what I do.
听说你的电影版权没卖出去
I heard you couldn't sell the movie rights.
现在流行的是真实犯罪迷你剧
It's all about true-crime limited series these days.
我们一起经历了那么多
After everything we went through together.
杜威会怎么想
What would Dewey think?
-这招真卑鄙 -你的书也一样
- That's a low blow. - So was your book.
你说我“精神不稳定” 是“天生的杀手”
You called me "unstable" and a "born killer."
你这是断章取义
That's taken out of context.
我这是直接引用
That's literally a quote.
你不觉得你写的东西
You don't think what you wrote has something
跟我们这次的遭遇有关系吗
to do with what's happening to us?
走吧
Come on.
嘿 我跟西德尼聊过了
Hey, I talked to Sidney.
-她不会来纽约 对吗  -不会来
-She's not coming here, is she? - No.
她要我代她问好 但她要带马克和孩子们去安全的地方
She sends her love, but she's taking Mark and the kids someplace safe.
她值得有一个圆满的结局
She deserves to have her happy ending.
这一点我们同意
On that much, we agree.
嘿 我跟你们一样想要抓到那个浑蛋
Hey, I want to catch this fucker as much as you do!
也许吧
Maybe.
也许你真正担心的是 如果没了鬼面的素材
Or maybe you're just afraid that without Ghostface in your life,
你会名气大跌
you're gonna fade away.
你们这些白痴 你们有危险了
You fools! You're in danger!
你们没看到吗 它们在追你们 在追我们所有人
Can't you see? They're after you! They're after all of us!
我们的妻子 儿女 每一个人
Our wives, our children, everyone!
他们已经来了 你们就是下一个
They're here already! You're next!
你们就是下一个
You're next! You're next! You're next! You're next!
是谁
Who is it?
明天才玩“不给糖就捣蛋”的游戏
You're a day early for trick-or-treating, you know.
（卡彭特 萨曼莎）
好了 书呆子们 听我说
Okay, nerds, listen up!
虽然这次的鬼面杀人案很可怕
As terrifying as this all is,
但我很高兴能有机会扳回一局
I'm actually glad I get a chance to redeem myself
上一次我猜错了凶手
for not calling the killers last time.
-对 -没关系 好的
- Yep. - It's fine. Okay.
依我看 有人是想把续集变成重续片
The way I see it, someone is out to make a sequel to the requel.
什么是重续片
Um, what's a requel?
你很漂亮 亲爱的 但等我说完再提问
You're beautiful, sweetie. Let's hold questions to the end.
《血腥刺杀1》发生在伍德小镇
Stab 1 took place in Woodsboro.
《血腥刺杀2》发生在大学里
Stab 2 took place in college.
所以我们推测凶手要模仿这些电影
So we think that the killer is trying to copy the movies?
有这个可能
That is one possibility.
主角在大学里 对上了
Heroes now in college: Check.
人物中增加了可疑的新角色 让嫌疑人和/或受害者
Suspicious new characters brought in to round out the suspect list and/or body count:
在数量上更丰富
Check, check and check.
-你们几个都对上了 -我不喜欢这样
I don't like this.
-但这不可能是《血腥刺杀2》的重演 -为什么
- But it can't just be about Stab 2. - Why not?
如果这是续集 这还说得通
It would make sense if this were just a sequel.
但我们不是在续集里 因为现在已经没人拍续集了
But we're not in a sequel, because nobody just makes sequels anymore.
我们是在电影系列里
We're in a franchise!
一个连贯的电影系列 需要遵守一定的规则
And there are certain rules to a continuing franchise.
-我就知道你会说这些 -第一条
- I had a feeling. - Rule one:
各方面的规模都超过以往
Everything is bigger than last time.
更多预算 更多角色 更多受害者
Bigger budget, bigger cast, bigger body count.
更长的追逐 还有枪战和砍头
Longer chases, shoot-outs, beheadings.
你得超越以往才能吸引人
You got to top what came before to keep people coming back.
-砍头  -砍头
- Beheadings? - Beheadings.
第二条：不管上一次是什么剧情 这次都反着来
Rule two: Whatever happened last time, expect the opposite.
系列电影只有颠覆预期才能生存
Franchises only survive by subverting expectations.
如果之前的凶手 是喜欢抱怨和过分敏感的电影迷
If the killers last time were whiny snowflake film nerds
有多个影评网站账号 却没有个性
with Letterboxd accounts instead of personalities,
那么这次你们可以反着猜
you can bet the opposite will be true here.
第三条：谁都没有安全牌
And rule three: No one is safe.
之前参演过的角色在新剧集里都是炮灰
Legacy characters? Cannon fodder at this point.
之所以让他们在新剧集里露脸 就是为了在怀旧时轻松干掉他们
Usually brought back only to be killed off in some cheap bid for nostalgia.
所以盖尔和可碧有危险哦
It's not looking too good for Gale and Kirby.
这还不是最糟糕的
Oh, and that's not even the worst part!
这时候她会跟我们说最糟糕的部分
This is the part where she tells us the worst part.
最糟糕的是
The worst part is
系列电影 只是给电影IP持续加热的分集影片
franchises are just continuing episodic installments designed to boost an IP.
这意味着在新剧集里 主角也完全可以舍弃
Which means main characters are completely expendable now, too.
比如劳瑞斯特罗德 南希汤普森 艾伦雷普利
Laurie Strode, Nancy Thompson, Ellen Ripley,
莎莉哈德斯蒂 电锯人 托尼史塔克 詹姆斯邦德…
Sally Hardesty, Jigsaw, Tony Stark, James Bond--
连卢克天行者也一样 他们都死了 这样系列电影才能接着拍
I mean, even Luke Skywalker-- all died so their franchises could live on.
这意味着有危险的 不仅仅是好友团里的伙伴
That means it's not just the friend group.
我们任何人都可能随时被杀
Any of us could go at any time,
特别是萨曼莎和塔拉
especially Sam and Tara.
-等等 任何人  -对
Wait, any of us? Yeah.
-我在这个好友团里  -对
Am I in the friend group? Yeah.
我是目标之一
Am I, like, one of the targets?
我会不会死了都还是处男
Am I gonna die a virgin?
你透露的信息让人有点尴尬
That was a weird overshare.
但让我们来看看目前的嫌疑人
But it brings us to our current suspects:
伊森
Ethan.
没人会怀疑这个呆里呆气的腼腆男生 因为他太呆和腼腆了
The shy, dorky guy who no one suspects because he's so shy and dorky.
我为什么会在嫌疑人名单里 就因为我无意中成了查德的舍友
Why am I on the suspect list? Because I'm randomly Chad's roommate?
抽签选室友是可以作假的
Roommate lotteries can be juked.
你可能为了接近我们而动了手脚
You could have fixed it to get next to us.
奎茵
Quinn.
风流的室友 这简直是恐怖电影的经典角色
The slutty roommate. A horror movie... ...classic.
应该是“性积极” 但谢谢
"Sex positive," but... thank you?
你是怎么成为萨曼莎和塔拉的室友的
Um, how did you come to live with Sam and Tara?
我回应了她们的在线招室友广告
I answered their ad online.
好了 别再说了 你的回答已经够可疑了
Okay, say no more. You've already implicated yourself enough.
那是个匿名广告 明迪
It was an anonymous ad, Mindy.
你也知道 我们调查过她 而且她的爸爸还是警察
And you know we vetted her. Plus her dad is a cop.
这让她更有可能是凶手
And that makes it more likely that she's the killer,
因为有个警察爸爸是绝妙的掩护
because having a cop dad is a great cover.
你不记得 恐怖电影是怎么演的了吗 塔拉
Do you not remember how these movies work, Tara?
她一直这样吗
Is she always like this?
最后是安妮卡
And finally... Anika.
永远不要相信恋爱角色
Never trust the love interest.
好吧 我们弄懂了规则 也列出了嫌疑人
Okay! So, we have our rules and we have our suspects.
等等 那你们呢
But wait. What about you guys?
我觉得我们可以放心地排除我们四个人
I mean, I think it's pretty safe to rule out the four of us
我们去年在伍德小镇经历过这种事
who went through this last year in Woodsboro.
-同意 -不同意
- Agreed. - Um, not agreed.
万一你们受到的创伤 导致你们中的一个或几个人发疯呢
What if the trauma you all went through caused one or more of you to snap?
对 或者你们从那些杀人事件中 获得的名气
Yeah, or the fame you got from the killings made you thirsty for more.
让你们渴望更加出名呢
I mean, let's be honest here,
老实说 网上关于萨曼莎的一些推论…
some of the theories online about Sam are--
你敢胡说试试看
Don't you fucking dare.
好吧 但她说得对
Okay, she's right, though.
我们面对事实吧
I mean, face facts--
如果我们都有嫌疑 那你们也有嫌疑
if we're all suspects, you're all suspects.
记得萨曼莎卡彭特的不在场证明吗  那个心理治疗师
Remember Samantha Carpenter's alibi, the therapist?
他被捅死了 从鼻子捅死的
He was stabbed to death. Through the nose.
从鼻子捅死的 这得多癫狂
Through the nose. How messed up is that?
是很癫狂
It's pretty messed up.
他听了萨曼莎的危险言论后举报了她 结果却死了
He turned her in for making threatening remarks, ended up dead.
你猜猜哪个病人的就医记录被偷了
And guess which patient's notes were stolen?
所以萨曼莎杀了自己的不在场证人 还偷了自己的记录
So Sam kills her own alibi and steals her own session notes?
也许吧
Maybe.
在现场又发现了一个面具
Another mask was found at the scene.
DNA跟罗曼布里格的匹配
It's a DNA match for Roman Bridger.
执导《血腥刺杀3》的鬼面杀手
The Ghostface who was directing Stab 3.
感觉他在给我们留真实的电影彩蛋
It's like he's leaving us real-life franchise Easter eggs.
以倒序的方式留下面具
Like dropping the killers' masks in reverse.
感觉杀手在进行某种倒数
Almost like he's counting down to something.
倒数到《血腥刺杀1》会发生什么
What happens when he gets to one?
目前我们一共有九名鬼面杀手
So we've had nine Ghostface killers so far.
九名 但是在电影里…
Nine. I thought in the movies--
别纠结电影了 电影不重要
Forget about the movies. The movies don't matter.
看 去年是安波弗里曼和里奇基尔希
Look. Last year was Amber Freeman and Richie Kirsch,
我们在第一个案发现场发现了他们的面具
whose masks we found at the first crime scene
就在两名电影学生的尸体旁边 而在那晚的早些时候
along with the bodies of two film students
这学生杀害了他们的教授
who killed their professor earlier that same night.
然后是吉尔罗伯茨和查理沃克 他们的面具被留在杂货店
Then it was Jill Roberts and Charlie Walker-- theirs at the bodega.
罗曼布里格是唯一单独作案的鬼面杀手
Roman Bridger was the only single Ghostface.
表扬一下他的远大志向
Kudos to him for ambition.
他的面具出现在心理医生的家里
His mask was found at the shrink's.
接下来就剩米奇阿尔蒂里 南希卢米斯 斯图马赫
Which leaves Mickey Altieri, Nancy Loomis, Stu Macher...
还有比利卢米斯 第一个鬼面杀手
...and Billy Loomis. Number one.
他也是头号嫌疑人的生父
And the father of our chief suspect.
做这件事的人要把我们再次引向萨曼莎
Well, whoever's doing this is leading us back to Sam.
我稍后再跟你谈
I will check in later.
让你女儿小心点
And tell your daughter to stay sharp.
接近卡彭特姐妹就是接近鬼面杀手
Proximity to the Carpenters is proximity to Ghostface.
嘿 杰克  你能给亚特兰大办事处打个电话吗
Hey, Jack? Would you call the Atlanta field office?
尽可能查清楚里德探员的背景
Dig up what you can on Agent Reed.
我觉得你应该离开纽约
I think you should get out of the city.
鉴于你上次的遭遇
You know, considering what happened to you last time.
我不会怪你的…
I-- I wouldn't blame you
如果你想走的话
if... you wanted to go.
你想得真周到
That's very thoughtful of you, but, um,
但我哪里也不去
I don't think I'm going anywhere.
你们能不能直接亲热起来
Will you two just make out already?
-这也太不合适了 -好吧 随便啦
That is so inappropriate, - dude. - Oh, whatever.
大胆上
Get it over with!
好了
Here you go.
-萨曼莎  -嗯
Sam? Yep?
我们没必要留在这里
We do not have to stay here.
很遗憾 我心意已决 抱团更安全
Well, too bad. I insist. Safety in numbers.
这会很有意思 核心四人组开睡衣派对
This'll be so fun. A little slumber party with the Core Four!
-核心四人组  -对
- "Core Four"? - Yeah.
-你给我们起了外号  -没错
- Did you give us a nickname? - I sure did.
我们一起经历了很多 而且这个外号很酷
We've been through a lot together, and it's a pretty cool nickname.
-有待商榷 -确实有待商榷
- That's debatable. - It's extremely debatable.
你不能这样给自己起外号 傻瓜
You can't just give yourself a nickname, dingus.
我当然能 傻瓜 因为我就起了
Of course I can, dingus, because I just did.
-核心四人组 举手击掌 -不要
- Core Four, up top! - No.
-低手击掌 -把手拿开
- Down low. - Get that away from me.
-来嘛 天啊 -别做这种事
Please, - for the love of God. - Don't do it.
我希望核心四人组的小伙伴
I would like a little more respect and support
能给我一些尊重和支持
from my fellow members of the Core Four.
-大伙儿 这是什么情况  -据命案组的…
-Guys. What the hell? -We're hearing from sources inside
消息人士透露
the homicide division
头号嫌疑人不是别人 正是萨曼莎卡彭特
that the prime suspect is none other than Samantha Carpenter,
她是2022年 伍德小镇杀人案的幸存者之一
one of the survivors of the Woodsboro killings in 2022,
昨晚有人看到她当街袭击一名女子
seen here attacking a woman on the street last night.
你有什么毛病
is wrong with you?
你对我有意见 住口
You got a problem with me? Knock it off!
你们离她远点 她做过什么自己清楚
Stay away from her. She knows what she did.
去年伍德小镇惨案发生后 网上谣言四起
In the wake of the Woodsboro tragedy last year, rumors sprouted online
称卡彭特实际上是那些命案的主使
that Carpenter was actually responsible for the killings,
她把罪责都推到了男友里奇基尔希身上
blaming the crimes on her boyfriend, Richie Kirsch
而少女安波弗里曼…
and teen Amber Free--
我知道你不喜欢我处理事情的方式
I know you're not a fan of the way that I've been handling things,
我也知道我一直让你很头疼
and that I've been giving you a really hard time.
但我可以说…
But I can say
我们谁都没法切身体会你的痛苦
that none of us can relate to what you are experiencing.
我真的很抱歉 让你独自承受这些
And I'm really, really sorry that you have to do that alone.
这不是你的错
It's not your fault.
我知道我不应该在乎别人的看法
And I know I shouldn't care what people think.
但被人这么讨厌感觉真的很糟糕
It just sucks being this hated.
嘿 提醒一下
Hey. Hey. Just a reminder,
在这间屋子里 没人讨厌你
not a single person in this room hates you.
好吗 我们都有不开心的经历
Okay? We have all been through some fucked-up stuff,
我们的应对方式各不相同
and we are coping with it differently.
但我们出于一个原因一起搬到了纽约
But, I mean, we moved here together for one very specific reason.
我们是一个团队
We are a team.
我们是核心四人组
We are the Core Fucking Four.
-太谢谢了 说得很对 -我恨自己
- Thank you very much. - Ah, I hate myself.
-你说出口了 -我就是这个意思
You said it. That is what I'm talking about.
我们是核心四人组
It's the Core Four.
-喊出来 -不 我不会喊的 现在不要
Say it. I'm not gonna say it.
-没错 我们是一个团队 但是… -喊起来很响亮
I mean, yes, we're a team, but... It's got a nice ring to it.
我跟走道对面的帅哥上床很久了
I've been sleeping with Cute Boy from across the hall.
-耶 -我就知道
- Boom! - I fucking knew it!
-我就知道不对劲 -你猜对了
- I knew it, I knew it. - You called it.
你那天露出吻痕时我就知道了
I knew it from the day you had that hickey.
在过去24小时里 三州地区的万圣节鬼面面具
Sales of the Ghostface Halloween mask across the Tri-State area in the last 24 hours...
（鬼面面具销量暴涨）
销量飞速增长
have gone through the roof!
-我买了面具 你呢  -你懂的
I've got my mask. What about you, Jay?
-这个万圣节一定很吓人 -没错
You know it. It's gonna be one spooky Halloween. I'll say.
现在我们转到盖伊那边 看看我们的天气
Now, let's get over to Guy for a look at our weather.
对 我知道她是我的室友 但你是警察
I know she's my roommate, but you're, like, the police.
-不 我知道 -嘿
No, I know. Hey!
该死
Fuck.
对 我能看到 你干什么 浑蛋
Hey, yeah. Wassup, bitch?
我看到你了 浑蛋
I see you, motherfucker.
萨曼莎
Sam! Samantha!
我觉得我们应该击一下掌
I feel like we should high five or something.
-核心四人组来击个掌 好吗  -别这么叫
The Core Four High Five-- may we, please?
但可以击掌
Don't call it that, but we'll do the high five.
-来啊 -继续
Come on.
好肉麻
Sam! Samantha!
萨曼莎 搞什么?
Sam, what the fuck?
她惊慌害怕 而且紧张多疑
She's really freaked out and paranoid.
-宝贝 你要一起吗  -等一下
Babe, you gonna join me? Hang on.
不要 别用我的洗面奶 它针对女性皮肤平衡了PH值
No. And don't use my good face wash. It's pH-balanced for women.
接电话呀 宝贝
Pick up your phone, baby.
（来电 丹尼）
是他吗
Is that him?
-不 塔拉 现在不合适 -嘿 你是认真的吗
- No, Tara. Not right now. - Hey, what are your intentions?
对 问得好
That's right.
没关系 我会回拨给他的
It's fine. I'll call him back.
可怜的家伙
Poor guy. Okay.
奎茵和她的绅士访客又开始了
Quinn and her gentleman caller are back at it again.
她也上床了 好吧
She's getting it, too? Okay.
救命 住手
Help! Stop!
塔拉 等一下
Tara, wait, wait!
快跑
Run.
大伙儿 快啊
Guys, come on!
噢 该死
Oh, fuck.
明迪
Mindy!
给我走开
Stay the fuck back!
嘿
Hey!
等等 查德
Wait, wait, Chad!
-她们还在上面 -该死
- They're still up there. - Shit!
该死
Fuck.
萨曼莎
Sam!
-你有钥匙吗  -我落在里面了
- Do you have the keys? - No, I left them inside!
明迪 关浴室门 快
Mindy, bathroom door. Hurry!
天啊 那个人死了
Oh, fuck! That guy's dead.
噢 该死
Oh, shit.
Oh, fuck.
嘿
Hey!
该死的
Shit.
别担心 我救你
Don't worry, I got you.
-你开玩笑吗  -你有更好的办法吗
- Are you fucking kidding me? - You have a better idea?
该死的 没有
Fuck. No.
一次过一个人
You have to come one at a time.
-你们俩先过 明迪 -什么 不
- You two go first. Mindy! - What? No.
得有人堵门 我会让安妮卡第二个上 快走
Someone needs to hold the door. I'll send Anika next. Go!
萨曼莎 来 眼睛看着我 宝贝
Sam, come on. Eyes on me, baby.
眼睛看着我
Keep your eyes on me.
噢 天啊
Oh, shit.
-噢 我的天啊 -我扶着 宝贝 我扶着
- Oh, my God. - I got you, baby.
宝贝 快
Baby, come on!
它撑不住我
It won't hold me.
好吧
Okay.
梯子不会掉下去的 它能撑住你 我保证
It ain't going anywhere. It's gonna hold you, I promise.
丹尼
Danny.
我稳着梯子 你不会掉下去的 快
I got you. You ain't going nowhere. Let's go.
-她流了好多血 -说些积极点的话
- She's losing a lot of blood! - Say something more positive!
看着我 萨曼莎 来 宝贝
Eyes on me, Sam. Come on, baby.
来 宝贝 我稳着你
Come on. I got you.
快 我稳着你
Come on, I got you.
好了
Okay.
-快来 -快过来
- Come on! - Let's go!
-快 明迪 -快来 我们得快点
- Come on, Mindy! - Let's go, we got to move!
安妮卡 快点
Anika, come on!
-安妮卡 -去 快去啊
Anika! Go! Come on!
-你得先走 -不行
You have to go first. I can't.
看着我 你得走
You have to go.
明迪 不要 我随后就跟上 我保证
Mindy, no! I'll be right behind you, I promise.
明迪 快 你得爬过来
Mindy, come on. You got to get over here!
快点
Let's go!
-我们稳着你 -就是这样 明迪
We got you. That's it. Mindy.
-稳当地慢慢爬 -我们稳着你
Slow and steady. We got you.
噢 天啊
Oh, God.
-很好 宝贝 快来 -快过来
Baby, you can't stop. Get over here right now!
安妮卡马上就跟上
Anika's coming right behind you.
-安妮卡 快来 -快
Anika, come on! Go!
-你可以的 -快啊 安妮卡
You can do it! Come on, Anika!
天啊 不行 我做不到
Oh, God! I can't do it, I can't do it.
-别往下看 -看着我
Don't look down! Look at me!
你可以的 你做得很好
You can do it! You're doing good.
怎么了
What?
安妮卡 你得马上过来
Anika, you have to move right now!
不 天啊 拜托 不要
No, God! Please, no!
安妮卡 你得快点
Anika, you got to move!
不
No!
你一定要过来
You have to make it!
宝贝 我不想死
Baby, I don't want to die!
不 安妮卡
No, Anika.
安妮卡 把手给我 我拉你
Anika, give me your hand. I got you.
嘿 你还好吗
Hey. You okay?
这不是你的错 萨曼莎
This isn't your fault, Sam.
就是我的错
But it is.
有人拿走了我们的刀
Someone took our knives,
所以我们没法反击
so we couldn't fight back.
我不知道究竟能相信谁
I don't know who I can trust.
那就谁都别信 别信你的朋友 也别信我
Then don't trust anyone. Not your friends. Not me.
谁都不要相信
Not anyone.
我还要问你几个问题
I have a few more questions for you.
这边 丹尼
Just this way, Danny.
查德
Chad.
-你去哪里了  -什么 什么时候
- Where were you? - What? When?
-昨晚 -什么 我有经济学的课 你知道的
- Last night! - What? I had Econ. You know this.
胡扯 你不见踪影 然后我的妹妹差点被杀
Bullshit, man! You disappear, and my sister almost gets killed!
兄弟 我和一百个人在自习室里学习 你可以问他们
Dude, I was in a study hall with a hundred other people. You can ask any of them.
该死的
Fuck, man.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
-是谁  -安妮卡和奎茵
Who? Anika and Quinn.
明迪 我很抱歉
Mindy, I'm so sorry.
离我远点
Step the fuck back.
你嫌疑最大
You're at the top of my list.
我在上经济学的课
I had Econ!
-在这里可以看到出口伤 -往前走 长官
Go right ahead, sir.
我马上回来
I'm gonna be right back.
关于奎茵的死 我很遗憾
I'm really sorry about Quinn.
谢谢
Thank you.
我的两个孩子都没了
Both my kids are gone.
我的整个家
My whole family...
都散了
...is gone.
上面不让我查这件案子了
They took me off the case.
但我不会停止调查的 直到找到凶手
But I'm not gonna stop until I find him.
谁伤害我的家人
You fuck with my family...
谁就得死
you die.
同意
Agreed.
嘿 你们还好吗 我一听说就赶来了
Hey, are you okay? I came as soon as I heard.
盖尔 我对天发誓…
Gale, I swear to God...
先休战 好吗 我是来帮你们的
Truce, okay? I'm here for whatever you need.
好吧 说得好听
Okay. Nice try.
我是说真的
Really, I am.
好 好吧 我不会公开报道 行吗
Okay, fine. Off the record, okay?
行 谢谢
Okay. Thank you.
抱歉我打了你
I'm sorry I punched you.
不 你没打
No, you're not.
我是没打
I'm not.
你是警察 对吗
You're the cop, right?
我调查了你的前两个受害者 然后有了新发现
I did some digging on your first two victims and I found something.
我知道面具是从哪里来的了
I know where the masks are coming from.
带我去
Show me.
女士们
Ladies.
可碧
Kirby?
盖尔
Gale.
-她是FBI探员 -她就是个小年轻
She's with the FBI.She's a child.
FBI什么时候招儿童了
When did they start letting children into the FBI?
-我30岁了 -但你看起来就像个受精卵
- I'm 30. - Well, you look like a zygote.
我配有枪 盖尔
I have a gun, Gale.
好吧 你肯定也想看那个地方
Okay, fine. You're gonna want to see this, too.
杰森和格雷格是亚特兰大的富家子弟
Jason and Greg were little Atlanta rich boys.
很明显 他们用假名租了这个地方
Apparently, they used fake names to rent this place.
你是怎么发现的
How did you find it?
新闻里有一种报道叫“调查报道” 是有原因的
It's called "investigative journalism" for a reason.
你怎么没查出来  你不是在追踪他们吗
How didn't you find it? Weren't you tracking them?
我多次查过他们的财务记录
I went through their financial records dozens of times.
这地方没在那些记录里 这说不通
This was not in any of them. Doesn't make sense.
没关系 是我的调查水平高 你也会有这一天的
Don't worry. I'm just really good at my job. You'll get there.
这是什么地方 安保人员在哪里
What is this place? What's with all the security?
这是个电影院
It's a movie theater.
这里不仅仅是电影院
It's not just a theater.
还是一个圣殿
It's a shrine.
他们收集了整个系列的物品
They've got the whole goddamn franchise.
（布拉德利音像出租店 加州 伍德小镇）
查德
Chad?
这是兰迪舅舅的物品
This was Uncle Randy's.
他们都集齐了
They've got everything.
-那是… -捅我的那把刀
Is that--The knife I was stabbed with.
你们都经历太多了
You all have been through so much.
这都是谁画的
Who drew all these?
（《伍德小镇凶案》《校园惊云》《末日之刃》）
（杜威莱利）
杜威
Dewey.
他们是怎么弄到这些的
Hey, how'd they get all this stuff?
这些不是物证吗
Isn't this evidence?
警察爱钱 而谎称证物丢失简直是小菜一碟
Well, cops like money, and evidence can get lost pretty easily.
当然不包括在场的两位警官
Present company excluded, of course.
我为什么要来这里  我的不在场证明得到了证实
Um, why am I here exactly? My alibi checks out.
为了能让我盯着你 室友
So I can keep an eye on you, roomie.
凶手在杀害杰森和格雷格之前 一定已经发现了这个地方
The killer must have found this place before he murdered Jason and Greg.
然后他将模特上的面具摘下来带走
And then he took the masks off the mannequins.
九个全带走了 从斯图到比利 再到安波和里奇
All nine, from Stu and Billy to Amber and Richie.
（比利）
天啊 这地方真酷啊
Hot damn! How fucking cool is this place?
才不酷
Fuck, no.
就是很酷
Fuck, yes.
得了 萨曼莎 你一定很高兴 能一起继续我们的事业
Come on, Sam, you got to be excited to get our murder on again. Together.
比利和萨曼莎 卢米斯小队
Billy and Sam. Team Loomis.
准备好再杀更多烂人吧
Get ready to slice up more motherfuckers.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
不知道
I don't know.
所以
So,
有人杀了那两个蠢人
somebody killed these chucklefucks
然后接手了
and took over?
那个人相信伍德小镇的命案 是萨曼莎主使的
Someone who believes that Sam masterminded Woodsboro.
如果这是普通的《血腥刺杀》 这会是杀手的幌子
If this were a normal Stab movie, this would be the killer's lair.
这意味着这不是普通的《血腥刺杀》
Which means this isn't a normal Stab movie.
这是砸死斯图马赫的电视
The TV that killed Stu Macher.
前提是你相信他真的死了
If you believe he's dead.
我听说你是个恐怖电影迷
I hear you're a horror fan.
说得对
It's been said.
拍得最好的《猛鬼街》是
Best Nightmare on Elm Street?
第一部
The original.
最好的《十三号星期五》是
Best Friday the 13th?
-第二部 -终结篇
Part II.The Final Chapter.
我一度很喜欢科里费尔德曼
Had a crush on Corey Feldman.
好吧 理解
Okay. Respect.
《惊魂记2》
Psycho II is...
-被低估了 -被低估了
...underrated.
《糖果人》 是原版好还是重续版好
Candyman. The original or requel?
-都好 -都好
Both. Okay.
好吧
Okay.
还算有两下子
Game recognize game.
你还好吗
You okay?
萨曼莎 我什么时候才能重新当个普通人
Sam, when do I get to be a normal person again?
我不知道
I don't know.
我不想卷进这种事里
I don't want to be a part of this.
我不想牵扯什么愚蠢的往事 就因为我…
I don't want to be a part of some stupid legacy because I'm--
全都怪我
Because of me.
对不起
I'm sorry.
别说了 萨曼莎
Just drop it, Sam.
塔拉
Tara.
我去找她
I got her.
听起来气氛很严肃啊
That seemed intense.
自从我重新走进她的生活后 我就…
Ever since I came back into her life, I've just...
搞得一团糟
made a mess of it.
嘿
Hey.
在这些事里 你妈妈人呢
Where's your mother in all this?
我跟塔拉说了比利的事后 她就不理我了
She cut me off when I told Tara about Billy.
然后塔拉也不理她 因为她不愿意跟我说话
Then Tara cut her off because she wouldn't talk to me,
所以现在我们都没有妈妈
so now neither of us have a mother.
很抱歉要这样说 但她真差劲
I'm sorry to say this, but fuck her.
我的父母也很差劲
My parents sucked, too.
但你仍然可以组建自己的家庭
But you can still make your own family.
即使你只有一个家人也可以
Even if it's just with one person.
如果你连这个家人也失去了呢
And if you lose that one person?
那就继续好好生活
You just-- You keep going.
也许你会找到另一个孤独者 然后你们彼此照应
And maybe you find another loner, and you look after each other.
你是怎么走出那段阴影的
How'd you get past what happened to you?
我被捅了之后 差点就死了
I almost died after I was stabbed.
严格来说 我确实死过
Technically, I did die.
死过四分钟
For four minutes.
当我康复后…
When I recovered...
我很恼火
I got mad.
我不想余生都活在对恶人的恐惧里
I didn't want to spend the rest of my life being afraid of monsters.
我要让那些恶人恐惧我
I wanted the monsters to be afraid of me.
我喜欢这态度
I like that.
抱歉打断你们
Sorry to interrupt.
我可能想到了一个 让那个变态碰壁的办法
Think I might have an idea about how to turn the tables on this creep.
好啊 我们加入
Yeah. We're in.
抱歉 盖尔 媒体人不得参与
Sorry, Gale. No press allowed.
这是警方的事务 我做本职工作也很出色
Police business. I'm good at my job, too.
你应该跟他们在一起
You should have stayed with the others.
那不可能
That's not gonna happen.
让两个人都陷入险境没有意义
There's no point in both of us putting ourselves at risk.
我不是陷入险境 我是当你的后盾
I'm not. I'm your backup.
我们正在做电影里从不管用的电话跟踪
So we're really doing the phone tracing thing that never works in the movies.
你会说：“继续跟他通话 萨曼莎 再说两分钟 我就快锁定他了”
It'll be all, "Keep him talking, Sam. Two more minutes, I've almost got him."
然后那个人 在我们马上就能锁定位置时挂了电话
And then he hangs up just before we can get a lock.
我可以在15秒内锁定位置
I can trace a call in under 15 seconds.
你让她们在外面当诱饵
Well, you've got them out there as bait.
因为凶手通常都在诱饵的附近打电话
Because the killer usually calls from somewhere nearby.
你觉得现在是白天 这里是公共场所 所以她们很安全
And you think they're safe because it's broad daylight in a public place?
有我在呢 好吗 贝利也在
Look, I am here, okay? And so is Bailey.
我们的兰迪舅舅就是这么死的
This is exactly how our Uncle Randy died.
在大白天的公共场合
Broad daylight. Public place.
被拖进一辆小货车里 然后被狂捅数刀 兰迪就这么没了
Yanked into a van. Stab, stab, stab. No more Randy.
萨曼莎 在外面不必紧张 好吗
Hey, Sam? Stay frosty out there, okay?
我们还好
We're good.
（来电 里奇基尔希）
-你死定了 -不 是你死定了 萨曼莎
You're gonna die, you know. No, you're gonna die, Samantha!
在我砍你妹妹的时候被自己的血呛死
Choking on your own blood while I hack up your sister.
说不定我们会先找到你
Unless we find you first.
作为主使 你真的不太聪明
For a mastermind, you're not very bright.
你想等我打电话给你 祈祷我就在附近 这样警察就能抓我
Waiting for me to call, desperately hoping I'm nearby so the police can grab me?
但我不在附近 我先你一步
But I'm not nearby. I'm a step ahead.
再见 萨曼莎
Be seeing you, Samantha.
锁定位置了吗
Did you get it?
锁定了 定位马上显示
Yep. Geolocation coming through right now.
（已定位）
他在上西城
He's on the Upper West Side.
他在城市另一头的公寓大楼里
He's inside an apartment building, halfway across the city.
-是西96街吗  -你怎么知道
- On West 96th? - How did you know that?
盖尔
Gale.
“媒体人不得参与‘’
"No press."
臭丫头 我上次见你时 你的毛还没长齐呢
Bitch, last time I saw you, you were in glee club.
请原谅 我不信你能保障她们的安全
Forgive me if I don't trust you to keep them safe.
-给你 宝贝 -谢谢
- Here you go, baby. - Thanks.
我的朋友丹尼在上西城工作 他可以更快赶到那里
My friend Danny works on the Upper West Side. He can get there quicker.
对 但他也可能会干掉她 他有可能是凶手吗
Yeah, or he could finish her off. Is it possible he's the killer?
该死 我们得尽快赶过去
Fuck. We have to get there now.
那里隔着50个街区 而且我们不知道 信息是否准确 等等
It's 50 blocks away. We don't even know if it's true.
-你花时间想想 -我们没时间了
- Sam, wait! Take a minute. - We don't have a minute.
你得相信我 我们得做正确的决定
You have to trust me, we got to make the right call.
-他已经… -萨曼莎
He's already-- Sam!
上车
Get in.
她在干什么
What's she doing?
嘿 从我的车上下来
Hey, get out of my car!
你们在干什么 那是警车
What do you think you're doing? That's an official vehicle! Hey!
我们要鸣笛吗
Should we use the sirens?
我们偷了警车当然要鸣笛啦
Did you think we'd steal a police car and not use the sirens?
-你有驾照吗  -该死 好了
- Do you have a license? - Fuck, yeah.
你们干什么
What are you doing?
那是警车 你们不能偷警车
It's a cop car! You can't steal a cop car!
应该是我们点的餐
That'll be our food.
你好
Hello?
不是送餐电话 是找你的
Not the food. It's for you.
是谁
Who is it?
请问您是哪位
May I ask who's calling, please?
他说是凶手
He says it's the killer.
-你好  -你好 盖尔
Hello? Hello, Gale.
你和我竟然没通过电话 真奇怪啊
Strange that you and I have never spoken on the phone.
我们早该通话了
This is long overdue.
我同意
I agree.
报警
Call the police.
我猜过了这么些年…
I figured after all these years...
（萨曼莎卡彭特）
你一定想采访我
you'd want an interview.
对 你猜对了
Well, you figured right.
你这次的动机是什么
So, what's your motive this time?
你对电影不满意还是想保持知名度
You angry at the movies or you just trying to stay relevant?
我也想问你同样的问题
I could ask you the same.
你不知道过往的角色是可以除掉的吗
Don't you know the legacy characters are disposable now?
没人在乎上个世纪的主角
Nobody cares about last century's heroes.
-那你为什么还找我  -可以说是念旧
Then why bother with me at all? Call it nostalgia.
或者你也许应该被惩罚
Or maybe you deserve to be punished
惩罚你利用别人的惨剧挣那么多钱
for all that money you made off the misery of others.
也许这次应该让别人 靠报道你的死讯挣钱了
Maybe it's time someone made a buck reporting your death.
你已经是第十个想杀我的鬼面杀手了 你知道吧
You know you're like the tenth guy to try this, right?
另外剧透一下
And spoiler alert,
戴面具的蠢人在剧终时永远不会得逞
it never works out for the dipshit in the mask.
但他们在死之前绝对会引起轰动 对吧
Oh, but they certainly leave a mark before they go, don't they?
里奇和安波成功捅死了杜威
Richie and Amber managed to butcher Dewey.
把他割得像圣诞烧鹅一样
Carved him up like a Christmas goose.
失去唯一一个爱过你的男人是什么感觉
How does it feel to lose the only man who ever loved you?
浑蛋
Fuck you!
知道你最后没在他身边是什么感觉
How does it feel to know that you weren't there for him at the end?
当满肚子刀眼的他躺在地上痛呼着死去时
Not there to give him comfort
你没在他身边给他安慰
as he died screaming in his own guts.
接下来在痛呼中死去的人就是你
You're the one who's gonna die screaming.
也许吧 但你看不到了
Maybe. But you won't be around to see it.
你没能阻止发生在杜威身上的惨剧
You couldn't stop what happened to Dewey.
就像你也阻止不了这一幕
Just like you're not gonna be able to stop this.
天啊
Oh, God!
这样怀旧感觉如何 浑蛋
How's that for nostalgia, fucker?
你没打中哦
You missed.
我肯定打中了
Sure I did.
你赢了 我正坐电梯前往一层
You win. I'm in the elevator heading for the ground floor.
可不是嘛
Sure you are.
也许你确实打中了我 也许我受伤了
Maybe you did hit me. Maybe I'm wounded.
或者也许我穿着防弹衣
Or maybe I'm wearing a bulletproof vest.
所以我要打你的头
That's why I'm gonna shoot you in the fucking head!
你真是当鬼面杀手的好苗子啊 盖尔
You would've made a good killer, Gale.
西德尼永远不够格 而杜威是粉丝最喜欢的角色
Sidney never would've made sense, and Dewey was the fan favorite.
所以如果你在压力之下精神崩溃
But you cracking under the pressure
变成了鬼面杀手 那将会是个绝妙的转折
and turning into Ghostface would've been a great twist.
继续说啊 浑蛋
Keep talking, asshole.
好啊 你想聊什么
Sure. What do you want to talk about?
你从来没机会当女主角 对吧
You never got to be the leading lady, did you?
一切总是围着西德尼甜心转 她抢走了所有的表现机会
It was always all about poor sweet Sidney, sucking up all the oxygen.
这样一来你还剩什么角色
What did that leave you to be?
聪明又性感的角色
The brains and the sex appeal.
抱歉杀了你的男友
Sorry about your boyfriend.
那一身肌肉没什么帮助
All those muscles didn't help much.
确实
They sure didn't.
你可以别挂吗
Can you hold, please?
浑蛋
Fuck you!
嘿 卑鄙鬼面男
Hey, fuckface!
盖尔
Gale!
天啊 盖尔
Oh, shit. Gale?
盖尔
Gale.
对不起
Sorry.
真对不起
I'm sorry.
我早应该想到他会来找你
I should've known that he was gonna come after you.
真对不起
I'm so sorry.
他没能杀死我
He didn't get me.
告诉西德尼
Tell Sidney
他从来都杀不死我
he never got me.
盖尔
Gale?
-盖尔 -盖尔
- Gale. - Gale.
盖尔 拜托
Gale? Please.
让一下
Out of the way!
-让一下 -让开 你得让开 快
- Out of the way! - Move. You got to move. Move!
不
No! No!
-让她们后退 -萨曼莎 快
Okay. Get them back, please. Sam, please!
-马上让她们让开 -请后退
- They need to move now. - Excuse me. Please step back.
-通知医院 -马上
Call it in. Right away.
-正在检查 -撑住 盖尔
Checking. Come on, Gale.
脉搏很弱 拿担架来
Got a weak pulse. Get the backboard.
得马上去医院
We need to move now.
担架 快走
Backboard! Let's move.
我尽快赶来了
I got here as fast as I could.
是吗
Did you?
我很害怕 大伙儿
I'm scared, you guys.
我不想再受伤害了
I really don't want to get hurt again.
我也不想
Neither do I.
我也不想你再受伤
I don't want you getting hurt again, either.
我知道
I know. I know.
我们现在怎么办
So what do we do now?
要不然这次就让他赢一次吧
Maybe he gets to win this time.
他想惩罚我
He wants to punish me.
我
Me.
那就让他惩罚吧
So maybe I let him.
我任他处置
I'll just give myself up.
如果只有这样做
If this is what I have to do
才能保障你们的安全…
to keep you safe,
那很值得
it's worth it.
不行 我们不能这样做 萨曼莎
No, we're not doing that, Sam.
你之前回伍德小镇保护我
You went back to Woodsboro to protect me.
每一天 你都决心要保护我
Every single day, you make the decision to protect me.
如果不是你 我们都活不成
None of us would even be alive if it weren't for you.
这次你要让我们保护你
You have to let us protect you this time.
-不要 -就要
- No. - Yes.
我们是一个团队 记得吗
We're a team, remember?
其实…
Actually,
我们就像是家人
we're a family.
我们上 核心四人组 快来
Let's go! Core Four! Come on.
-核心四人组 -快啊
- Core Four. - Come on.
-核心什么  -这是我们的外号
- Core what? - It's an us thing.
他会来找我们
He's gonna keep coming after us.
有没有一个可以安全藏身的地方
Isn't there somewhere safe we could just hole up in?
不行 他会不停地找我们
No, he's gonna keep finding us.
好吧
Great.
但我们可以利用这个思路
We could use that, though.
我不愿意停止调查这个案子 已经被上级狠狠训斥了
I'm getting my ass chewed out for not dropping the case
你们现在还要我做什么
and now you want me to do what?
我们要引他到一个稳妥的地方 在里面伏击他
We want to lure him to a secure location and trap him inside.
然后呢
And then what?
除掉他
We execute him.
你要帮我们吗
Are you gonna help us?
我们干掉那个浑蛋
Let's kill the son of a bitch.
我没法离开警局 但盖尔把影院的门禁卡给了我们
Now, I'm stuck here, but Gale gave us the keycards to the theater.
那有严密的监控和安全摄像头 但我们可以利用这一点来对付他
It's got heavy surveillance and security cameras, but we can use that against him.
我让可碧在那里跟你们碰头 我会尽快加入你们
I'll tell Kirby to meet you there. I'll join you as soon as I can.
-明白了 -记住 乘坐公共交通工具
- Got it. - And remember, travel in public.
你们身边的人越多
The more people around you, the less chance he has
他就越难以在你们到达之前下手
to take a shot at you before you get there.
这真的是个好计划吗
Is this even a good plan?
你不想去的话可以不去
You don't have to come if you don't want to.
你这是让我离队 然后让凶手逐一下手吗 我不要 谢谢
So we just peel off and the killer picks us off one by one? No, thank you.
我们去影院 快 进去
Let's just get to the theater. Come on, in here.
对 因为在连环杀手的电影院里动手 会没那么可怕
Yes, because it'll be much less scary at the serial killer movie theater.
该死
Fuck.
等等 嘿 查德
Wait, hey, hey! Chad!
嘿 该死的 查德
Hey! Fuck! Chad!
塔拉
Tara!
-等等 明迪呢  -查德 萨曼莎 嘿 萨曼莎
- Wait, where's Mindy? - Chad! Sam! Hey, Sam!
明迪
Mindy! Mindy! Mindy!
快来 该死
Let's go. Shit.
该死的
Fuck!
见鬼
Fuck.
别拿你的鬼脸对着我 鬼面杀手
Get your Ghostface ass away from me, Ghostface.
离我远点
Go away.
-明迪在哪里  -她没赶上地铁
- Where's Mindy? - She missed the train.
我本来要等她的 但那个帅哥把我拽上车了
I was gonna wait for her, but Cute Boy here dragged me on.
-我只是想把大家聚在一起 -靠分开我们
- Trying to keep us together. - By pulling us apart?
没事 没关系 她和伊森在一起
It's okay. It's fine. She's with Ethan.
（我搭乘下一趟）
她会在影院跟我们会合
She'll meet us there.
这是开往南码头的地铁一号线
This is a South Ferry bound local one train.
天啊
Oh, shit.
下一站是79街车站
The next stop is 79th Street.
我们要乘坐多少站
How many stops do we have?
十站
Ten.
本站是79街车站
This is 79th Street.
这是开往南码头的地铁一号线
This is a South Ferry bound local one train.
下一站是72街车站
The next stop is 72nd Street.
（查德 你上下一趟地铁了吗 ）
（上了 和鬼面伊森在一起）
（正在发送）
这是开往南码头的地铁一号线
This is a South Ferry bound local one train.
下一站是79街车站
The next stop is 79th Street.
抱歉
Sorry!
明迪还是没回复
Still nothing from Mindy.
本站是72街车站
This is 72nd Street.
大伙儿
Guys?
下一站是66街林肯中心车站
The next stop is 66th Street, Lincoln Center.
嘿
Hey.
讨厌
Fuck you.
这是开往南码头的地铁一号线
This is a South Ferry bound local one train.
下一站是66街林肯中心车站
The next stop is 66th Street, Lincoln Center.
本站是66街林肯中心车站
This is 66th Street, Lincoln Center.
下车时请注意站台和列车之间的缝隙
As you exit, please be careful of the platform and the train.
糟了
Oh, shit.
明迪 该死的
Mindy! Fuck!
天啊 明迪
Shit, shit. Mindy!
天啊 流了很多血
Fuck, that's a lot of blood.
来帮忙 快来帮忙
Help! Somebody help!
该死 我得带你下车 好吗
Fuck. We got to get you out of here, okay?
该死的
Damn it.
-我们走 -该死的
Come on! Fuck.
该死 大家帮忙报警
Shit. Somebody call 911!
-天啊 -你还好吗
-Oh, my God. - Are you okay?
好 好得很
Yeah, I'm so good.
你会没事的
You're gonna be okay. You're gonna be okay.
该死的 我又猜错了
Goddamn it. I got it wrong again.
怎么搞的
What the fuck?
快来帮忙
Help!
对 我们需要医疗救助 在66街车站
We need medical assistance. We're at the 66th Street station.
该死的系列电影
Fuck this franchise.
嘿
Hey.
贝利跟我通气了 我布置好了场地
I talked to Bailey. I've got everything set up.
-明迪和伊森在哪里  -他们比我们晚五分钟
- Where are Mindy and Ethan? - They're five minutes behind us.
我带你们进去
Let's get you all inside.
-你别进了 -什么
- Not you. - What?
别相信任何人 记得吗
Don't trust anyone, remember?
我们跟你不熟悉
We don't know you.
不太熟悉
Not really.
你熟悉我呀
You know me.
你不是从伍德小镇一起来的
You're not Woodsboro.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
没关系 我理解
It's okay. It's okay, I get it.
注意安全 好吗
Be safe, okay?
好吗
Okay?
你也是
You, too.
做得对
Good call.
我在你们到之前检查过了
I cleared the whole place before you got here.
这是唯一的进出口
So, this is the only way in or out.
当他迈进第一道门后
He steps in through the first door,
两道门会自动锁起来 把他困在里面
both doors lock automatically, trapping him inside.
我们把它变成一个杀戮空间
We turn it into a kill box.
-武器呢  -一把枪 我来拿
- Weapons? - One gun, and I hold onto it.
我是唯一一个持有警徽的人 所以由我来持枪
I am the only one with a badge here and that's the way it's gonna be.
我们在这里很安全
We're safe here.
我要联系明迪 看看他们是不是快到了
I'm gonna check in with Mindy. See if they're close.
快接呀
Come on, come on.
嘿 是我 给我留信息吧
Hey, you've reached me. Leave a message.
你知道在这里不安全
You know you're not safe here.
每当有人说：“我们在这里很安全”时 这表明不安全
Whenever someone says, "We're safe here," it means you're not.
-别在这时候出现 -但你的聪明不止于此 萨曼莎
Not now. But you're smarter than this, Sam.
拿起武器 自己检查场地
Grab a weapon and clear this place yourself.
你知道我说得对
You know I'm right.
选得好
Excellent choice.
这是我最喜欢的刀
My favorite.
可碧
Kirby?
Kirby!
喂
Hello?
让大家都离开那里 萨曼莎 你们不安全
Get everyone out of there, Sam. You're not safe.
我收到了亚特兰大办事处的消息
I heard from the Atlanta field office.
他们说自从伍德小镇去年发生那些命案后
They said Agent Reed's been on a downward spiral
里德探员的状态就越来越差
ever since the Woodsboro-murders last year.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
他们两个月前 因为她精神状态不稳定辞退了她
They fired Kirby two months ago for being mentally unstable.
-什么  -她已经不是FBI探员了
What? She's no longer with the FBI.
-听着 浑蛋 -不 是你听着 小贱人
Listen, asshole. No, you listen, you little bitch.
你敢挂我的电话 我就像杀鱼一样剖了你 明白吗
Hang up on me, I'll gut you like a fish. Understand?
-你想怎么样  -看看你里面长什么样
What do you want? To see what your insides look like.
天啊
Oh, shit.
别人最近一次用这个地方是什么时候
When was the last time anybody used this place?
这里好老旧
It's so old.
抱歉 你拿吧
Um. I'm sorry, you can have them.
-你拿 -不 我的意思是…
- Take them. - No, I mean...
你想要的话 给你
If you want them, you have them.
-你觉得我想要这个  -也许吧
- You think I want these? - Kind of.
它们已经有一百岁了
They're a hundred years old.
也许你会感兴趣
Maybe that's your thing.
我其实…
I actually--
我想吻你想很久了 这可能有点尴尬
It's maybe embarrassing how long I've wanted to do that.
你应该早点吻我的
Yeah, you should've done that a lot sooner.
我知道
I know.
你还可以多多吻我
But you could also do it a lot more times.
塔拉
Tara!
塔拉 我们走 快 快点
Tara, let's go. Come on, come on!
快 快跑
Come on, go, go, go!
-是可碧 她是凶手 -天啊
It's Kirby. She's the killer. No shit!
-被锁起来了 这边 -我们被困了吗
- That's locked. Come on. - Are we trapped?
她把整个影院变成了一个杀戮空间 要杀戮我们
She made this whole theater a kill box. For us.
嘿 那里怎么样 有一个出口
Hey, what about that? There's an exit door.
也许能通往屋顶或别的地方
Maybe it leads to the roof or something?
要弄清楚只有一个办法 我们走
There's only one way to find out. Let's go.
贝利在来的路上了 但…
Bailey's on the way, but--
该死
Oh, fuck!
砍头
Beheadings!
塔拉 快
Tara! Come on.
看镜头笑一个 浑蛋
Smile for the camera, motherfucker!
这边 快
This way! Come on!
她应该从前门跑出去
She should be running out the front door.
去你的
Get fucked!
塔拉 走 快走
Tara, go! Go!
不
No!
查德
Chad!
快跑
Run.
走啊
Go.
-这边 上这里 快 -韦斯卡彭特执导的电影一样
This way. Up here. Come on.
每个人都有嫌疑
Everybody's a suspect.
你不害怕 对吗
You're not scared, are you?
噢 萨曼莎
Oh, Sam!
没有动机时才更可怕
It's a lot scarier when there's no motive.
准备好了吗
Ready?
你要准备好 准备好了吗
I need you to be ready. Ready?
看着我
Look at me.
我准备好了
I'm ready.
来啊 浑蛋
Come on, motherfucker!
没事了
It's okay!
-离我们远点 -我们知道凶手是你 可碧
- Stay the fuck back! - We know it's you, Kirby.
有个凶手把我打晕了
One of them knocked me out.
可碧 站住 离这两个姑娘远点
Kirby, stop! Get away from the girls!
你这是做什么
What are you doing?
你是不是杀了奎茵  你是不是杀了我女儿
Did you kill Quinn? Did you kill my daughter?
一派胡言
Jesus Christ!
不管他跟你们说过什么 都不要相信
Whatever he's been saying to you, don't listen to him.
他可能就是凶手
He's probably the killer.
你后面有人
Behind you!
漂亮
Great job.
都干得好
Both of you.
-是你  -对 当然是我
- You? - Yeah, of course me.
老实说 你们对我们做了那种事 我以为你们很厉害
Frankly, I expected more from the two of you after what you did to us.
你说“我们”是什么意思
What do you mean, "us"?
嗒哒
Ta-da!
明迪说对了 在室友抽签中作假很简单
Mindy was right. It was easy to juke the roommate lottery.
为了接近你们
All I had to do to meet you
我只需要跟自大又自负的查德当室友
was room with a conceited, condescending alpha literally named Chad.
天啊 杀死他的感觉真好
Fuck, it felt good to kill him!
这是你奶奶的 萨曼莎
This was your grandmother's, Sam.
南希卢米斯
Nancy Loomis?
你们家的人 流淌着连环杀手的血液 对吗
Really runs in your fucking family, doesn't it?
-说到家人… -听好了
Speaking of family... Wait for it.
我不叫伊森兰德里…
...my name's not Ethan Landry,
对吧 爸爸
is it, Dad?
“爸爸”
"Dad"?
等等 如果你们是凶手 那剩下的这个…
Wait. If it's you two, that just leaves...
是明迪
Mindy?
嘿 室友
Hey, roomies.
你们没想到吧
You didn't see that one coming, did you?
-对 因为你死了 -其实并没死
- Yeah, because you died! - Kind of didn't, though.
那是摆脱嫌疑的好办法
It was a good way to get off the suspect list.
让我可以毫无忌惮地捅盖尔威瑟斯 在地铁上捅明迪等等
Stab Gale Weathers, stab Mindy on the train. That sort of thing.
对 我那时确保第一个赶到案发现场
Yep, and I just made sure I was first on the scene
这样就可以用新鲜的尸体把她换出来了
so I could switch her body out with a fresh one.
用一些假血和一个假体
Little fake blood, a prosthetic.
你们想不到一个悲痛的父亲 可以做到什么程度来瞒天过海
You'd be amazed at what a grieving father can get away with.
我拿了斯图马赫的面具
I got Stu Macher's mask.
他是我最喜欢的杀手
He was my favorite.
很好 这是第三个
Nice. That's number three.
那是第二个
That's two.
最后是…
Which leaves...
你父亲的面具
your father's.
我们就是在倒数这个 萨曼莎
This is what we've been counting down to, Sam.
把面具戴上
I'm gonna need you to put it on.
滚开
Fuck you!
不准靠近她
Stay the fuck away from her!
别激动
Come on.
怎么 这是什么情况
What? What is this?
你们是家庭合伙作案
You did this as a family?
对 贱人 你应该比任何人都熟悉这种做法
Hell yeah, bitch! You should know better than anyone.
她们还是不明白
They're still not getting it.
我不知道你们轻信了什么谣言
I don't know what you believe,
但伍德小镇的案子不是我做的 不是我
but I didn't commit those murders in Woodsboro. It wasn't me!
我们知道 当然不是你
We know that. Of course you didn't.
你以为我们要杀你 是因为听了可笑的阴谋论
You think this is based on some bullshit conspiracy theory?
拜托 你以为最早散布谣言的人是谁
Come on. Who do you think started the rumors about you in the first place?
你知道把萨曼莎
Do you know how easy it was
从伍德小镇的英雄 变成大恶人有多简单吗
to turn Sam from the hero of Woodsboro into the villain?
你知道引导其他人
How easy it is to convince the world
相信大恶人 而不是相信大好人有多简单吗
to believe the worst in people rather than the best?
因为现在光把人杀死还不够
Because it's not enough to just kill someone these days.
还要让那个人身败名裂
You have to assassinate their character first.
所以当爸爸“发现”你们千疮百孔的尸体
So when Dad here "discovers" your horribly mutilated bodies...
再加上萨曼莎戴着生父的面具
...posed with Sam wearing her father's mask,
他会宣称 某个轻信谣言的白痴在网上看到了
he'll say some poor dumb bastard read on the Internet
你才是真正的鬼面杀手的言论
that you're the real Ghostface
然后“行侠仗义”杀了你 代替法律伸张正义
and took matters into their own deluded hands.
没错 这会是完美的谎言
Exactly! That's why it's the perfect alibi.
最好的谎言一向是半真半假
And all the best lies are based on the truth.
而你恰好是杀人犯
And you're a killer.
-就跟你父亲一样 -不 我不是
- Just like your father. - No, I'm not!
是 你就是 你这个贱人 你杀了我们的哥哥
Yes, you are, you motherfucker! You killed our brother!
你在胡说什么
What are you talking about?
你说过你哥哥是因为车祸去世的
You said your brother died in a car accident.
不 亲爱的 白痴
No, no, no, you sweet, dumb thing.
他是在伍德小镇死的
He died in Woodsboro
死在了你这个贱人姐姐的手上
at the hands of your bitch sister.
你们是里奇的家人
You're Richie's family.
对
Yeah.
快跑
Ding-ding-ding-ding!
-现在她终于明白了 -快
She's finally starting to get it. Now!
我是看到了那张照片
It wasn't until I saw that photograph
看到了你对他做的事才下定决心的
of what you'd actually done to him that I knew.
我决心要杀了你 要你血债血偿
That I knew you had to fucking die! You had to be punished!
此外所有碍事的人都得死
Along with anyone else who stands in our way.
抓到她了
There she is.
抓到了这个该死的凶手
There's the fucking killer.
-我想说 你真会养育孩子 -闭上你的臭嘴
Great parenting job, by the way. Shut your whore fucking mouth!
-该死 -你还好吗
Shit. You okay?
我是完美的父亲吗 不是
Have I been a perfect Dad? No.
我有没有放纵里奇迷恋这些电影  也许有
Have I maybe overindulged Richie's love of these little movies? Yeah, maybe.
我觉得它们就是有点黑暗而已
For me, they're just a little dark.
但是…
But...
里奇极其痴迷这些电影
Richie really loved them.
他喜欢这些电影
He loved them!
他甚至自己制作了几部影片
He even made a few of his own.
你们知道吗
Did you know? Did you know?
你们觉得我没有发布节日特辑
So you think I didn't post a holiday special.
我试过 我真的试过
Well, I tried to. I really did try.
我可以跟大家互动
That I could interact with.
一个父亲和他的第一个孩子
There's a very special bond between a father
总是感情特别深厚
and his first son.
所以我帮他搜集了这些收藏
Which is why I helped him build this collection.
这都是他的
This was all his?
对 他是个狂热的收藏家 而且他还启发了其他人
Yes, he's a very passionate collector. And he inspired others.
我们得杀掉那两个 想要成为鬼面杀手的电影学生
We had to kill those two wannabe film students
因为你得死在我们手上 萨曼莎
because, well, we had to kill you first, Sam.
我把影院放在了他们的名下
I put the theater in their name,
这个影院 本来应该由我这个贝利好警探发现的
then good old Detective Bailey would've just stumbled on it,
但我没能这样做 因为天啊
but I didn't have to because, by golly,
那个盖尔威瑟斯还真是个有能耐的记者
that Gale Weathers is one hell of a journalist.
我为儿子建了一个“纪念碑”
I built a tribute to my son.
因此你得死在这里 萨曼莎
Which is why this is where you have to die, Sam,
死在他心爱的所有物品之中
surrounded by all the things he loved the most.
然后呢 你们杀了我们之后直接消失
What happens next? After you're done with us you just disappear?
不 我们会迅速赶到医院
No! We got to hurry over to the hospital
让明迪和盖尔活不成
and make sure Mindy and Gale don't pull through.
因为你们每个人都得死 萨曼莎
Because everybody dies, Sam!
和我儿子的痛苦和死亡 有关的所有人都得死
Everyone who had anything to do with the death of my son suffers and dies.
-对 -没错
- Fuck yeah, they do! - Yeah!
现在把面具戴上
Now put on the mask.
他生前
He was...
真差劲啊
...so pathetic.
才不差劲
That's not true.
就差劲 你的儿子…
Yeah, your son,
他就是个巨婴 杀人的事都让女朋友来干
he was a man-baby who made his girlfriend do all the killing.
他是个强悍和刚阳的年轻人
He was a strong, virile young man!
他就是个没用的烂人 在我割喉之前哭喊得不像样
He was a limp-dick little fuck who cried before I slit his throat.
给我闭嘴
Shut the fuck up!
萨曼莎 快
Sam, come on!
记得这个吗
Recognize this?
滚开
Fuck you!
抱歉 但我需要这个
Sorry, but I kind of need this.
把他捅烂
Fuck 'em up.
你能怎么办 贱人
What are you gonna do about it, bitch?
啊
Fuck!
萨曼莎
Sam!
我去找救援
I'll get help.
当心
Be careful.
来
Come on.
杀掉她
Go get her. Get her!
-我抓不住你 -可以的
I can't grab you. It's okay.
我抓不住
I can't grab on. I can't grab on.
不
No!
我早就想“捅”你了 塔拉
I've always wanted to stick something in you, Tara.
-浑蛋 -浑蛋
- Fuck you! - Fuck you!
现在你们要完蛋了
You guys are so fucked now!
萨曼莎
Sam.
Sam?
-放开我 -不
- Let me go. - No!
对 放开她 萨曼莎 快啊
Yeah, let her go, Sam, come on.
该死
Fuck!
-相信我 -该死的
-Trust me. - Fuck!
你得对我放手
You have to let me go.
抓到你了
Gotcha!
现在当个死处男吧
Now die a fucking virgin.
看来你又失去了一个哥哥
Looks like you're down another brother.
永远要射击头部
Always got to shoot them in the head.
该死
Oh, fuck.
哈喽
Hello.
你看到你的男朋友了吗
Do you see your boyfriend anywhere?
我现在根本没有男朋友
I don't even have a boyfriend right now.
你想要一个吗
Would you like one?
我根本不认识你 而且我不喜欢你
I don't even know you and I dislike you already.
（来电 萨曼莎卡彭特）
你好啊 贝利警探 我想问你一个问题
Hello, Detective Bailey. I've got one question for you.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
什么问题
What's that?
你最喜欢哪部恐怖电影
What's your favorite scary movie?
“最喜欢哪部恐怖电影”
"Favorite scary movie."
我这样问是因为你现在就在恐怖电影里
I'm asking because you're in one now.
在我的恐怖电影里
You're in my movie.
看来你穿上了真正属于你的衣服 对吧
I see you've put on your true face, huh?
你生来就是杀人犯
Your birthright.
你就要穿这身衣服受死了 多有诗意
Poetic that you're gonna die in it.
这就是你想要的 不是吗
This is what you wanted, isn't it?
现在你知道事实了吧
Now you know the truth, huh?
你身上流着杀人犯的血
Murder's in your blood!
别装神弄鬼了 快出来
Stop fucking around and show yourself!
小心我让你“如愿以偿”
Be careful what you wish for.
好了 我可是警察
All right, I'm a fucking police officer.
你觉得警方会怎么看 萨曼莎  你觉得他们会相信谁的话
How do you think this is gonna go, Sam? Who do you think they're gonna believe, huh?
应该会相信活人说的话吧
Probably the one who's still alive.
不
No! No!
我的父亲是个杀人犯
My father was a murderer.
不管你怎么想
No matter what you think,
我都不是那种人
I'm better than that.
谢谢
Thank you.
但你确实伤害了我们的家人 所以…
But you did fuck with our family, so...
-漂亮 -谢谢
- Nice. - Thanks.
你还好吗
You okay?
不好
No.
谢谢你对我放手
Thank you for letting me go.
我知道你能照顾好自己
I knew you could take care of yourself.
我想参与你的生活
I want to be in your life,
但只在你愿意的情况下才参与
but only as much as you want me to be.
我愿意
I want you to be.
我保证之后会认真做心理治疗
I promise you I'm gonna get so much therapy after this.
我是说真的
I'm serious.
我们会走出去的
We're gonna get through this.
一起走出去
Together.
我在一部恐怖电影里看过这剧情
I saw that in a scary movie once.
萨曼莎 嘿
Sam. Hey.
那边有两个人 快
Two over there. Let's go.
-你还好吗  -还好
- Are you okay? - Yeah.
我猜你们可能需要支援
I thought you might need some reinforcements.
另外我给西奈山医院打电话问了 明迪和盖尔不会有事
And I called Mount Sinai, and Mindy and Gale are gonna be okay.
明迪正赶过来 他们拦不住她
Mindy's on her way here now. They couldn't stop her.
还不赖 帅哥
Not bad, Cute Boy.
谢谢
Thanks.
如果你需要我就打电话
If you ever need me, call.
现在我们都是在鬼面杀人案中 受创伤的人了
We're all part of the same fucked-up family now.
当过往的角色并不总是坏事
And legacy doesn't always have to be a bad thing.
好的
Okay.
嘿
Hey.
我为查德难过
It's just Chad.
嘿 这边还有一名幸存者
Hey, we got another one here!
当心 让一让
Watch out, coming through.
-天啊 -查德
-Oh, my God. - Chad! Chad!
你还活着
How are you alive?
核心四人组
Core Fucking Four.
抱歉 你可能需要吸氧
Sorry. You probably need that.
天啊 你们还好吗
Oh, my God! Are you guys okay?
我知道谁是凶手了 是伊森和贝利
I know who the killer is! It's Ethan and Bailey.
-还有奎茵 -还有奎茵 该死的
- And Quinn. - And Quinn? Fuck!
我又错过了凶手的独白
Did I miss the monologue again?
你还好吗
Are you okay? Are you okay?
你们看起来不太好
You don't look okay.
天啊 我们都活着 这真是个转折中的转折
Oh, my God, we all survived. It's a twist on a twist.
医生给我用了很多止痛药 你们应该用一点这种药
They gave me a lot of drugs. You guys should get some of these drugs.
现在我的肩膀以下都没知觉
I can't feel anything below my shoulders.
萨曼莎
Sam.
走吗
Coming?
不是每部电影都有彩蛋啦
Not every movie needs a post-credit scene.